<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-us">
    <author>
        <name>Blizzard Entertainment</name>
    </author>
    <title type="text">Diablo III™</title>
    <id>4</id>
    <updated>2012-09-14T16:08:19.321Z</updated>
    <entry>
        <title type="text">Dev Journal: Defensive Bonuses and Monster Damage</title>
        <published>2012-09-14T16:00:00.000Z</published>
        <updated>2012-09-14T16:08:19.321Z</updated>
        <id>7155884</id>
        <link href="http://us.battle.net//d3/en/blog/7155884"/>
        <summary type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p><span style="font-size: 12px; ">In 1.0.5, we will be reducing the defensive bonuses provided by some
                    of the more powerful skills and skill runes. </span> 
                    <span style="font-size: 12px; ">In addition to reducing defensive bonuses, we're also going to be
                        nerfing incoming monster 
                    </span>
                    <em style="font-size: 12px; ">even more</em>
                    <span style="font-size: 12px; "> to compensate, which should open up more build options for players
                        progressing through the higher difficulty levels.
                    </span>
                </p>
            </div>
        </summary>
        <content type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>We're taking a close look at defensive skills vs. incoming monster damage in 1.0.5. We’re going to be
                    changing a few defensive skills for each class, including some direct nerfs to skills like wizard
                    Energy Armor and barbarian War Cry - Impunity. However, we're also reducing incoming damage in
                    Inferno, so players will actually come out ahead. In short the plan is:
                </p>
                <ol>
                    <li>Reduce the effectiveness of select defensive skills</li>
                    <li>Reduce monster damage by more than the mitigation lost by these skills</li>
                    <li>Putting both changes together, players actually take less damage than before</li>
                </ol>
                <p> </p>
                <div class="ctextheadline">
                    <img src="http://us.media5.battle.net/cms/content_folder_media/PPWV73X5AC8P1346202513358.jpg?v=0"
                         style="width: 590px; height: 56px; "/>
                    <h1>
                        Why We're Making This Change
                    </h1>
                </div>
                <p class="pullquote"
                   title="High incoming monster damage combined with extremely powerful defensive skills make those skills and runes feel mandatory.">
                    Why are we doing this? The reason is not complicated. High incoming monster damage combined with
                    extremely powerful defensive skills make those skills and runes feel mandatory. Our goal is that by
                    simultaneously nerfing defensive skills and reducing incoming damage, players who choose to continue
                    using these defensive skills will take less damage overall, and players who choose to forego these
                    "mandatory" skills will find themselves more survivable than what you would currently experience on
                    live. Overall, these changes result in a huge buff in the player’s favor. Just how mandatory are
                    these skills?
                </p>
                <p>
                    <br/>
                    As it is now, Energy Armor is used by 83% of level 60 wizards. Also, take a look at the distribution
                    of the War Cry skill on level 60 barbarians:
                    <br/>
                     
                </p>
                <p style="text-align: center;">
                    <a class="lightbox"
                       href="http://us.media4.battle.net/cms/gallery/TYMIO49ZLIVR1347503513788.jpg?v=1">
                        <img alt="" src="http://us.media4.battle.net/cms/gallery/TYMIO49ZLIVR1347503513788.jpg?v=1"
                             style="width: 325px; height: 287px; "/>
                    </a>
                </p>
                <p>In developing Diablo III, defensive skills were made potent because we wanted to ensure they would be
                    attractive. In some regards, we were too successful. Many players feel compelled to grab every
                    defensive skill available to them, which can take away from some flexibility in using different
                    build options.
                    <br/>
                    <br/>
                    This also creates problems for a class that may have less defensive skills. When one class has
                    massive defensive buffs, abilities like Mortar, Arcane Enchanted, and Plagued can feel pretty
                    modest, and at the same time feel overly punishing to a class without them. We’re all in favor of
                    people being able to build their character for survivability, but there needs to be a balance.
                </p>
                <p> </p>
                <div class="ctextheadline">
                    <img src="http://us.media5.battle.net/cms/content_folder_media/KFLQB5KCVNPO1346202513254.jpg?v=0"
                         style="width: 590px; height: 56px; "/>
                    <h1>
                        How Much is Enough?
                    </h1>
                </div>
                <p>So the stated goal is to make sure the combination of the defensive skill nerf combined with the
                    reduced damage from monsters still results in an overall buff to players. Let's bust out some math!
                    As previously mentioned, Energy Armor is one of the skills being impacted. The exact change is the
                    base armor provided by Energy Armor is being reduced from 65% to 35%, and the resistance increase
                    provided by Prismatic Armor is being reduced from 40% to 25%.
                </p>
                <p>
                    <br/>
                    The benefit of these skills is greater at higher levels of Armor and Resistance, so let’s assume
                    very high numbers of each. Suppose a wizard has 6000 Armor and 800 Resist before Prismatic Armor.
                    Assuming a level 63 enemy:
                </p>
                <ul>
                    <li>In 1.0.4 this translates to 9900 Armor (75.86% mitigation) and 1120 Resist (78.05% mitigation)
                        with Prismatic Armor, for a total mitigation of 94.70%
                    </li>
                    <li>In 1.0.5 this will be 8100 Armor (72.00% mitigation) and 1000 Resist (76.05% mitigation) with
                        Prismatic Armor, for a total mitigation of 93.29%
                    </li>
                    <li>If a monster hits for 50,000 damage, then the damage taken by the wizard will go from 2650
                        damage to 3355 damage.
                    </li>
                    <li>This means incoming damage would have to be less than 79% of the current value (2650 /3355) in
                        order for it to feel the same after 1.0.5.
                    </li>
                </ul>
                <p>Based on this it’s clear that in order to ensure 1.0.5 is a net buff for all wizards we’d have to
                    reduce incoming monster damage by at least 21%. Prismatic Armor still provides a significant boost
                    to survivability, but it should no longer feel mandatory, opening up other options such as a more
                    offensively minded Storm Armor (which is getting buffed in 1.0.5).
                    <br/>
                    <br/>
                    Let’s do another example with the barbarian. War Cry Impunity is being reduced from 50% resistances
                    to 20%.
                </p>
                <ul>
                    <li>A barbarian with 800 resist before War Cry against a level 63 enemy translates to 1200 Resist
                        (79.21% mitigation) with Impunity in 1.0.4
                    </li>
                    <li>In 1.0.5 this will be 960 Resist (75.29% mitigation) with Impunity</li>
                    <li>If a monster hits for 20,000 damage after Armor, then the damage taken by the Barbarian will go
                        from 4158 damage to 4942 damage
                    </li>
                    <li>This means incoming damage would have to be less than 84% of the current value on live
                        (4158/4942) in order for the game to feel the same.
                    </li>
                </ul>
                <p class="pullquote" title="we’re going to reduce all damage in Inferno by at least 25%">As it happens,
                    we’re going to reduce all damage in Inferno by at least 25%. Players who want to be the toughest
                    damage mitigators in the game can continue to use defensive skills and get a sizable bonus for doing
                    so. Players who want to use other skills can do so without sacrificing such a massive amount of
                    survivability. Class builds that don't currently use heavy mitigation skills such as Smoke
                    Screen-focused demon hunters or Gargantuan-tanking witch doctors will find their survivability has
                    gone up considerably due to reduced incoming monster damage.
                </p>
                <p> </p>
                <div class="ctextheadline">
                    <img src="http://us.media2.battle.net/cms/content_folder_media/DO3TXX2498TV1346202513188.jpg?v=0"
                         style="width: 590px; height: 56px; "/>
                    <h1>
                        Class by Class
                    </h1>
                </div>
                <p>Here's a quick rundown of what's changing in terms of defensive skills in 1.0.5.</p>
                <div class="d3class">
                    <p>
                        <strong><img alt="" src="http://us.battle.net/d3/static/images/hero/barbarian/crest.png"/>
                            Barbarian:
                        </strong>
                    </p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>War Cry - Impunity: Bonus resistance reduced from 50% to 20%.</li>
                        <li>Leap - Iron Impact: We’re adjusting the design of this skill. Rather than providing 300%
                            armor for 4 seconds, it’s going to provide 100% armor per target hit for 3 seconds. So if
                            you don't hit any targets, you won't get any armor. If you hit 5 targets, you'll actually
                            get 500% armor. We are making this change because the intended fantasy of Iron Impact is a
                            barbarian who leaps into the thick of battle and is super tough. The way the skill plays out
                            on live it is essentially an Ignore Pain that can also move you. For the most part it is
                            better than Ignore Pain, making not only Ignore Pain unattractive, but also the other Leap
                            Attack runes. In 1.0.5, if you want a defensive cooldown - grab Ignore Pain. If you want to
                            leap into the thick of battle and be super tough, take Iron Impact.
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </div>
                <div class="d3class">
                    <p>
                        <strong><img alt="" src="http://us.battle.net/d3/static/images/hero/demon-hunter/crest.png"/>
                            Demon Hunter:
                        </strong>
                    </p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>In the case of the demon hunter, the class is a bit too binary. If you're playing a glass
                            cannon Smoke Screen build, then you're invulnerable most of the time, and when you make a
                            mistake, you die instantly. If you're using Shadow Power - Gloom with a legacy Natalya's
                            set, then you have near constant uptime of 65% damage reduction, but if you're not using the
                            legacy Natalya's set, Shadow Power - Gloom is a luxury.
                        </li>
                        <li>Independent of the general defensive skill nerf, we had already decided to buff Shadow Power
                            to last longer. The primary purpose of Shadow Power is to give you a short window of time
                            during which you can unload some damage to recoup some Life. Unfortunately the 3-second
                            duration makes this awkward to use. We are changing Shadow Power from 20% Life Steal for 3
                            seconds to 15% Life Steal for 5 seconds. This should be a modest buff to the skill as well
                            as making it a lot more pleasant to use. All of the runes are scheduled to see similar
                            changes, such as Blood Moon going from 30% Life Steal for 3 seconds to 25% Life Steal for 5
                            seconds. Each rune effect is slightly smaller, but for 5 seconds instead of 3 seconds,
                            resulting in an overall buff over the duration of the effect.
                        </li>
                        <li>Taking into account the across-the-board nerf to defensive skills, Gloom will become 35%
                            damage reduction for 5 seconds.
                        </li>
                        <li>This developer journal is focused primarily on defensive skill changes, but because the
                            change to Gloom is significant, I want to mention that we are looking at concrete mechanics
                            changes to the demon hunter to introduce new play styles. Many players have mentioned that
                            outside of Gloom, demon hunters seem to lack defensive options. More importantly, demon
                            hunters would like some different play styles, and we agree! Here are a few changes we are
                            adding for demon hunters in 1.0.5 to open up new ways to play:
                        </li>
                        <li>We are adjusting some runes and passives to provide ways to increase survivability that
                            scales with your Life, Armor, and resistances.
                        </li>
                        <li>We are changing the Spider, Boar, and Wolf companion pets to be actual pets that can tank
                            for you like a Gargantuan or Zombie Dog.
                        </li>
                        <li>We are putting a short cooldown on Sentry, but you can have two out simultaneously. On top
                            of that, the Custom Engineering passive will let you have a third Sentry turret! This opens
                            up a whole new play style for the Demon Hunter of establishing a "nest" that you can draw
                            enemies into.
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </div>
                <div class="d3class">
                    <p>
                        <strong><img alt="" src="http://us.battle.net/d3/static/images/hero/monk/crest.png"/>Monk:
                        </strong>
                    </p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>The strongest monk defensive skill is One With Everything. We've mentioned it before and it
                            bears repeating - this is something we would like to fix someday, but we're going to take
                            our time. Changes to One With Everything heavily impact existing monk gear. We still plan on
                            addressing this in the future but will do so in a way that does not invalidate the gear
                            monks have invested in.
                        </li>
                        <li>Resolve: Damage reduction reduced from 25% to 20%.</li>
                        <li>Seize the Initiative: Changed to grant 50% of your Dexterity as Armor. This will result in
                            anywhere from 750 to 1250 armor for most monks (depending on your Dex) which is comparable
                            to the mitigation lost by other classes. The reduction to Resolve and Seize the Initiative
                            should mean if you want to be a “super-tanky monk” you can still take all three defensive
                            skills, but it should be a lot easier to pick some other passives without feeling like
                            you’re going to blow up at the first Elite pack you encounter.
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </div>
                <div class="d3class">
                    <p>
                        <strong><img alt="" src="http://us.battle.net/d3/static/images/hero/witch-doctor/crest.png"/>
                            Witch Doctor:
                        </strong>
                    </p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>Jungle Fortitude is being reduced from 20% to 15% damage reduction.</li>
                    </ul>
                </div>
                <div class="d3class">
                    <p>
                        <strong><img alt="" src="http://us.battle.net/d3/static/images/hero/wizard/crest.png"/>Wizard:
                        </strong>
                    </p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>Energy Armor: Armor increase reduced from 65% to 35%.</li>
                        <li>Energy Armor - Prismatic Armor: Resistance increase reduced from 40% to 25%.</li>
                        <li>It’s worth noting that we’re going to provide additional alternative defensive options for
                            the wizard such as adding flat melee damage reduction to Ice Armor and creating a Familiar
                            variant that provides passive Life regeneration.
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </div>
                <div class="ctextheadline">
                    <strong>
                        <img src="http://us.media2.battle.net/cms/content_folder_media/6BNTULK3ZBG61346202513289.jpg?v=0"
                             style="width: 590px; height: 56px; "/>
                    </strong>
                    <h1>
                        Why You Nerf Inferno?
                    </h1>
                </div>
                <p>Alright, so let's recap. Defensive skills are taking a hit in 1.0.5, but incoming damage from
                    monsters is also being reduced. Taken together, the changes mean Inferno is going to be easier. For
                    some of you this is totally cool; you welcome an easier Inferno because it’s about efficiency and
                    not difficulty. For others, you may be skeptical but you're at least intrigued at the possibility
                    that you'll be able to drop some defensive skills and discover some new builds. However, for others,
                    Inferno is currently already too easy. Maybe you don't use any defensive skills; maybe your gear is
                    so good you dropped War Cry - Impunity weeks ago. For this last group you may be wondering "Another
                    Inferno nerf? But I crave more of a challenge, not less!"
                    <br/>
                     
                </p>
                <p class="pullquote"
                   title="1.0.5 is bringing the ”Monster Power” system...in short this is a callback to the Diablo II ”players X” option">
                    For people in this last group, 1.0.5 is bringing the "Monster Power" system. The details of this
                    system will be outlined as we get closer to 1.0.5, but in short this is a callback to the Diablo II
                    ”players X” option, allowing you to increase the level of challenge for increased rewards. Our hope
                    is that we can make Inferno easier while simultaneously providing new ways for top-end players to
                    gauge their increasing power in tangible ways.
                    <br/>
                    <br/>
                    We’re going to lock comments here, and ask that you instead head to
                    <a href="http://us.battle.net/d3/en/forum/topic/6571517430#1" target="_blank">this forum thread</a>
                    to let us know what you think.
                </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p>
                    <em>Wyatt Cheng is a Senior Technical Game Designer for Diablo III, and he’s annoyingly excited
                        about Netrunner being re-released as a Living Card Game. It’s really starting to get on
                        everyone’s nerves.
                    </em>
                </p>
                <style type="text/css">
                    #blog .detail div.ctextheadline {
                        position: relative;
                        display: block;
                        text-decoration: none;
                        line-height: 1 !important;
                        font-family: Georgia !important;
                        margin-left: 3px;
                    }

                    #blog .detail div.ctextheadline h1 {
                        position: absolute;
                        top: 17px;
                        left: 30px;
                        color: #FFBF55 !important;
                        font-size: 23px !important;
                    }

                    #blog .detail img {
                        -moz-border-radius: 4px;
                        -webkit-border-radius: 4px;
                        border-radius: 4px;
                        -moz-box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                        -webkit-box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                        box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                        border: 1px solid #300E0D;
                        max-width: 570px !important;
                        padding: 1px;
                    }

                    #blog .detail td:hover > a img, #blog .detail a img:hover {
                        border: 1px solid #BA5E0B;
                    }

                    #blog .detail .d3class {
                        min-height: 120px;
                        margin-bottom: 50px;
                        clear: both;
                    }

                    #blog .detail .d3class ul li {
                        margin-left: 40px;
                    }

                    #blog .detail .d3class img {
                        -moz-border-radius: 0px;
                        -webkit-border-radius: 0px;
                        border-radius: 0px;
                        -moz-box-shadow: 0 0 00px #000000;
                        -webkit-box-shadow: 0 0 00px #000000;
                        box-shadow: 0 0 00px #000000;
                        border: none;
                        width: 100px;
                        height: 100px;
                        margin-left: 10px;
                        margin-right: 10px;
                        padding-right: 15px;
                        float: left;
                    }

                    .pullquote:before {
                        content: "\201C" attr(title) "\201D";
                        font-size: 1.2em;
                        display: block;
                        float: right;
                        width: 8em;
                        margin: 0.25em 1em 0.5em 0;
                        padding: 1em;
                    }</style>
                <style type="text/css">
                    #page-comments {
                        display: none;
                    }</style>
            </div>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="text">Blizzard Comic Contest Winner</title>
        <published>2012-09-14T15:45:00.000Z</published>
        <updated>2012-09-14T00:12:01.879Z</updated>
        <id>7207167</id>
        <link href="http://us.battle.net//wow/en/blog/7207167"/>
        <summary type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>And the comic contest winner for August, 2012, is ...
                    <strong>Heather Scoggins  (Theodel).</strong>
                </p>
            </div>
        </summary>
        <content type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>And the comic contest winner for August, 2012, is ...
                    <strong>Heather Scoggins  (Theodel).</strong>
                </p>
                <p>The talented winner will receive a<a href="http://us.blizzard.com/store/details.xml?id=1100001962">DC
                    Unlimited StarCraft® Premium Series 2: Tychus Findlay Action Figure</a>. Congratulations!  In
                    September, we’ll be giving away a
                    <a href="http://us.blizzard.com/store/details.xml?id=1100001819">SteelSeries Diablo® III Headset</a>
                    to the winner of the next Blizzard Comic Contest.
                </p>
                <p style="text-align: center;">
                    <a href="http://us.battle.net/wow/en/media/comics/?view#/comic-2012-09-01" target="_blank">
                        <img alt=""
                             src="http://us.media5.battle.net/cms/content_folder_media/J85HEZCYBNQY1347394480446.jpg?v=1"
                             style="width: 188px; height: 118px;"/>
                    </a>
                </p>
                <p><a href="http://us.blizzard.com/en-us/community/contests/comic/rules.html">Keep those comics
                    coming</a>, and you might be the next artist to take home a prize! Also, be sure to set aside some
                    time to check out our<a href="http://us.battle.net/wow/en/media/comics/#/1">Warcraft</a>and
                    <a href="http://us.battle.net/sc2/en/media/comics/#/1">StarCraft</a>
                    comic sections. 
                </p>
                <style type="text/css">
                    #blog .detail img {
                        -moz-border-radius: 4px;
                        -webkit-border-radius: 4px;
                        border-radius: 4px;
                        -moz-box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                        -webkit-box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                        box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                        border: 1px solid #372511;
                        max-width: 570px !important;
                        padding: 1px;
                    }

                    #blog .detail td:hover > a img, #blog .detail a img:hover {
                        border: 1px solid #CD9000;
                    }</style>
                <p> </p>
            </div>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="text">The Voices of Diablo III, Part One</title>
        <published>2012-09-13T17:00:00.000Z</published>
        <updated>2012-09-13T00:26:36.577Z</updated>
        <id>7054209</id>
        <link href="http://us.battle.net//d3/en/blog/7054209"/>
        <summary type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>We rounded up a few of the actors behind Diablo III's most memorable voices, and chatted with them
                    about the time they spent working on the game. To begin, you'll hear from the actors behind Azmodan,
                    Tyrael, and Covetous Shen.
                </p>
            </div>
        </summary>
        <content type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>We recently rounded up a few of the actors behind Diablo III's most memorable voices, and chatted
                    with them about the time they spent working on the game. Today, we’d like to share our conversations
                    with Jonathan Adams (Tyrael), David Sobolov (Azmodan), and James Hong (Covetous Shen).
                </p>
                <p>Click on the tabs below to read each Q&amp;A, and keep watch for more to come in the future.</p>
                <table class="table2">
                    <tbody>
                        <tr>
                            <th>
                                <div class="goose" onclick="osTabSelect(this,1);">
                                    Tyrael
                                </div>
                                <div class="duck" onclick="osTabSelect(this,2);">
                                    Azmodan
                                </div>
                                <div class="duck" onclick="osTabSelect(this,3);">
                                    Covetous Shen
                                </div>
                            </th>
                        </tr>
                    </tbody>
                </table>
                <div id="osContentDiv">
                    <div>
                        <div class="sorTable">
                            <b class="fancyTitle">Jonathan Adams - Tyrael</b>
                            <br/>
                            <p><strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>So, how’d you get into this whole voice acting gig?
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>JONATHAN:</strong>
                                Well, I was a professional stage actor for like 15 years, and then I came out to LA and
                                started doing TV. While I was a stage actor, I would do the occasional voice gig on the
                                side. My wife has always said, “You should do voice over,” and when I was in Chicago I
                                went for a few auditions, and they didn’t quite work out. When I got to LA, I was doing
                                this television show
                                <em>American Dreams</em>
                                for a while, and I asked my manager if he knew any agencies that might be able to hook
                                me up. One of the first things I booked was the voice of [the] Buick [car company] -- I
                                was the voice in all the Buick commercials for something like 3 years. Then I started
                                doing a few animation jobs -- the first good-sized animation thing I did was for Marvel
                                Studios. I was Dormammu in the Dr. Strange animated movie. That was fun, and it just
                                started going on from there. What I really found was that my stage acting training, and
                                the fact that I was able to translate it to what I did on camera helped me translate it
                                all into voice acting.
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>One thing that’s different about video games as opposed to
                                voicing animation is player activity and the fact that your lines will sometimes get
                                repeated when there’s an appropriate gameplay trigger. The player has to go somewhere,
                                so you’re telling them, “Go left, go left, go left!” How do you handle that -- do you
                                feel like your stage training prepared you, or is it a totally different experience?
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>JONATHAN:</strong>
                                I don’t consider [guiding player activity] part of what
                                <em>I</em>
                                can do -- I feel like I just try to be as honest as possible when I’m doing anything --
                                that’s my litmus test. “Do you believe it, Jonathan?” is what I ask myself every time
                                I’m acting, over and over, in different permutations. If I believe it, and I’m honest
                                with myself, then I feel like the player will believe what I’m saying is a natural,
                                honest thing.
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>Slight segue -- have you had a chance to play Diablo III at
                                all?
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>JONATHAN:</strong>I’m a gamer; I do play games, and I just got my copy . . . and
                                then I moved. It’s still in a box. I really can’t wait to find it in one of the boxes we
                                have lying around and start playing. I’m gonna be a monk . . . or the demon hunter.
                                Those are the ones that appeal to me the most. I like stealth, quiet, and not too much
                                fuss and muss -- I like to get it over with.
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>What sort of cues do you get when you’re in the recording
                                booth? Do you get to see yourself or your character in motion, or do you get concept art
                                references?
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>JONATHAN:</strong>We get a lot of concept art, and what was really great for
                                Diablo III is that we got to see a few of the cinematics before they were completely
                                animated, so we had a strong idea of the storyline’s size and scope. These characters
                                are almost Shakespearean; they’re absolutely larger than life, they deal with incredible
                                things, but you have to keep them full and realized and human as well, otherwise the
                                audience turns off. I’d also look at the Diablo III website whenever I could, because
                                that was an interesting clue to the direction the series was heading.
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>Did you know the trajectory of Tyrael’s character arc, and what
                                was going to be happening from the beginning of your work, or is that something that got
                                parceled out as you got more lines?
                            </p>
                            <img src="http://us.media3.battle.net/cms/gallery/BAVR9ZWD2IT01347387544252.jpg?v=0"
                                 style="float: right;"/>
                            <p>
                                <strong>JONATHAN:</strong>
                                What was interesting was . . . it changed a few times during the time I was doing it.
                                First it was “How long is Tyrael gonna be the Stranger?” “How long before he realizes
                                he’s an angel?” “What does the Stranger know about being an angel?” “Once Tyrael has the
                                knowledge that he’s an angel, but also has the limitations of being mortal, where does
                                that leave him?” So, I got that information parceled out, and then, during a big
                                three-month arc of work, I got a really good picture of what Tyrael was going to be.
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>You brought the Stranger up, and that ties into another
                                question. We asked you to pack a lot into one character voice. How do you voice a
                                character who is both a human and an angel and has this very different vocal modulation
                                and confidence level at different parts of the game? Do you prep in a certain way for
                                voicing two sides of the same character?
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>JONATHAN:</strong>
                                <img src="http://us.media3.battle.net/cms/gallery/CWZ40AYZ4YKQ1347387544211.jpg?v=0"
                                     style="float: right;"/>My basis for Tyrael was Tyrael as man AND angel. “How would
                                a person sound if he knew he was once an angel, but now has human limitations?” That
                                kind of juxtaposition is fun to play with in fantasy and science fiction -- you get
                                characters like Data on Star Trek who’s so much fun to watch, because he’s human and
                                robot, and you’re watching him struggle with what that means. That’s what makes those
                                characters fascinating. What I did is [project] what Tyrael would be if he knew nothing
                                about being an angel, and he was simply human, and he had just woken up. That character
                                was the original character, minus his divinity. And then, later on, he was the same
                                character -- but minus his humanity. The baseline was the human &amp; divine character,
                                who could be haughty at times, like “I’m above it all,” but he loves humans, he loves
                                people.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>
                                “Subtracting the humanity” sounds like a hard thing to do.
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>JONATHAN:</strong>Well, you think of yourself as detaching from the human race.
                                Humans are . . . not exactly below you, but not quite up to where you are, like a dog or
                                a cat. You still love your dog, you still feed your dog, but you’re not gonna have a
                                conversation with your dog and expect him to answer you. You always know they’re not
                                like you.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>
                                You’ve got a period in Act 3 where you’re fighting alongside the player -- you must have
                                done a lot of fight recording, a lot of sword-swinging type stuff. What was that like?
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>JONATHAN:</strong>
                                 [<em>laughs</em>] I don’t like fighting in games. It’s a hard vocal couple of days.
                                It’d be the same as trying to fight -- not the same exactly, but your whole body gets
                                completely tired. You get very, very worn out. When I was in college, my friends and I
                                had a band; we played one live gig in front of a bunch of people. I was the singer, I
                                sang the whole time, and by the end of it my voice was shot. I hadn’t realized how hard
                                I’d been singing because I was so incredibly nervous. Those fighting days are just like
                                that. You’re so worn out -- to me, it’s incredible. It takes a lot out of you. But we
                                stretched the recording sessions out.
                            </p>
                            <p>You also have different kinds of fighting. “Ok, you just got hit by a big sword.” [<em>
                                vocalizes</em>] “Aaagh.” “Ok, now you got hit by a dagger.” [<em>vocalizes</em>] “Egh.”
                                Different sounds for different things.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>
                                Is it all sort of the same “fight session” recording?
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>JONATHAN:</strong>
                                We’ll have two or three recordings that’ll be two or three hours each of<em>just</em>
                                fighting, because you can’t really do more than that. You’re swinging your sword, you’re
                                blocking, you get hit, you’re hit with a spell. You’re running all over the place.
                                “El’druin!” keeps coming out. Those kinds of things.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>
                                The story of Diablo is pretty dark, it’s fairly bloody, it’s a little brutal, lots of
                                people die -- how do you have fun with something like that?
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>JONATHAN:</strong>
                                I like fantasy, I like science fiction -- I was a D&amp;D player when it was just a
                                little cardboard box with pamphlets in it, and your characters were fighter, thief,
                                wizard, cleric . . . .
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>Oh, man, the Red Box. Classic. Good times.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>JONATHAN:</strong>
                                You had those six-sided, ten, twenty, twelve, four-sided dice; it was a lot of
                                imagination-based fun. I used to play Neverwinter Nights and games like that, Icewind
                                Dale, every Sid Meier’s Civ game. To me, it’s just fun -- it doesn’t really affect me
                                that much.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>
                                I wanted to ask you a question about the craft, too. Do you think that if someone is
                                extremely hard-working and determined, sends out a lot of samples and reels, and really
                                tries, is that enough to get involved in voice acting, or is it more that you have to
                                have a certain voice in order to find your niche?
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>JONATHAN:</strong>There are all kinds of voices in voice acting. Everything. The
                                fact that I have a deep, powerful voice is a leg up for me, and it puts me in a bunch of
                                different niches as an actor. But I also think that the main thing you need to do is not
                                necessarily get yourself out there, but to practice. Like any instrument, you have to
                                learn to play it. Fortunately, I’ve had on-the-job training over the past 5 years. I
                                think that the quality of the performances I’m doing now is a lot better than what I did
                                when I did that first Dormammu character on Dr. Strange. I don’t just rely on the fact
                                that my voice is deep and strong. I really think acting is a craft. Talent
                                <em>helps</em>
                                -- if you have talent for it, that’s great -- but it’s not gonna get you all the way
                                there, nor will just doing a lot get you there. I’d say it’s like 70% craft, 30% talent.
                                Your talent will help your craft, but you really have to keep working at it.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>
                                Jon, thanks so much for your interview.
                            </p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div class="sorNoTable" id="osContainer1">
                    <div>
                        <div class="sorTable">
                            <b class="fancyTitle">Jonathan Adams - Tyrael</b>
                            <br/>
                            <p><strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>So, how’d you get into this whole voice acting gig?
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>JONATHAN:</strong>
                                Well, I was a professional stage actor for like 15 years, and then I came out to LA and
                                started doing TV. While I was a stage actor, I would do the occasional voice gig on the
                                side. My wife has always said, “You should do voice over,” and when I was in Chicago I
                                went for a few auditions, and they didn’t quite work out. When I got to LA, I was doing
                                this television show
                                <em>American Dreams</em>
                                for a while, and I asked my manager if he knew any agencies that might be able to hook
                                me up. One of the first things I booked was the voice of [the] Buick [car company] -- I
                                was the voice in all the Buick commercials for something like 3 years. Then I started
                                doing a few animation jobs -- the first good-sized animation thing I did was for Marvel
                                Studios. I was Dormammu in the Dr. Strange animated movie. That was fun, and it just
                                started going on from there. What I really found was that my stage acting training, and
                                the fact that I was able to translate it to what I did on camera helped me translate it
                                all into voice acting.
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>One thing that’s different about video games as opposed to
                                voicing animation is player activity and the fact that your lines will sometimes get
                                repeated when there’s an appropriate gameplay trigger. The player has to go somewhere,
                                so you’re telling them, “Go left, go left, go left!” How do you handle that -- do you
                                feel like your stage training prepared you, or is it a totally different experience?
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>JONATHAN:</strong>
                                I don’t consider [guiding player activity] part of what
                                <em>I</em>
                                can do -- I feel like I just try to be as honest as possible when I’m doing anything --
                                that’s my litmus test. “Do you believe it, Jonathan?” is what I ask myself every time
                                I’m acting, over and over, in different permutations. If I believe it, and I’m honest
                                with myself, then I feel like the player will believe what I’m saying is a natural,
                                honest thing.
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>Slight segue -- have you had a chance to play Diablo III at
                                all?
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>JONATHAN:</strong>I’m a gamer; I do play games, and I just got my copy . . . and
                                then I moved. It’s still in a box. I really can’t wait to find it in one of the boxes we
                                have lying around and start playing. I’m gonna be a monk . . . or the demon hunter.
                                Those are the ones that appeal to me the most. I like stealth, quiet, and not too much
                                fuss and muss -- I like to get it over with.
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>What sort of cues do you get when you’re in the recording
                                booth? Do you get to see yourself or your character in motion, or do you get concept art
                                references?
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>JONATHAN:</strong>We get a lot of concept art, and what was really great for
                                Diablo III is that we got to see a few of the cinematics before they were completely
                                animated, so we had a strong idea of the storyline’s size and scope. These characters
                                are almost Shakespearean; they’re absolutely larger than life, they deal with incredible
                                things, but you have to keep them full and realized and human as well, otherwise the
                                audience turns off. I’d also look at the Diablo III website whenever I could, because
                                that was an interesting clue to the direction the series was heading.
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>Did you know the trajectory of Tyrael’s character arc, and what
                                was going to be happening from the beginning of your work, or is that something that got
                                parceled out as you got more lines?
                            </p>
                            <img src="http://us.media3.battle.net/cms/gallery/BAVR9ZWD2IT01347387544252.jpg?v=0"
                                 style="float: right;"/>
                            <p>
                                <strong>JONATHAN:</strong>
                                What was interesting was . . . it changed a few times during the time I was doing it.
                                First it was “How long is Tyrael gonna be the Stranger?” “How long before he realizes
                                he’s an angel?” “What does the Stranger know about being an angel?” “Once Tyrael has the
                                knowledge that he’s an angel, but also has the limitations of being mortal, where does
                                that leave him?” So, I got that information parceled out, and then, during a big
                                three-month arc of work, I got a really good picture of what Tyrael was going to be.
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>You brought the Stranger up, and that ties into another
                                question. We asked you to pack a lot into one character voice. How do you voice a
                                character who is both a human and an angel and has this very different vocal modulation
                                and confidence level at different parts of the game? Do you prep in a certain way for
                                voicing two sides of the same character?
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>JONATHAN:</strong>
                                <img src="http://us.media3.battle.net/cms/gallery/CWZ40AYZ4YKQ1347387544211.jpg?v=0"
                                     style="float: right;"/>My basis for Tyrael was Tyrael as man AND angel. “How would
                                a person sound if he knew he was once an angel, but now has human limitations?” That
                                kind of juxtaposition is fun to play with in fantasy and science fiction -- you get
                                characters like Data on Star Trek who’s so much fun to watch, because he’s human and
                                robot, and you’re watching him struggle with what that means. That’s what makes those
                                characters fascinating. What I did is [project] what Tyrael would be if he knew nothing
                                about being an angel, and he was simply human, and he had just woken up. That character
                                was the original character, minus his divinity. And then, later on, he was the same
                                character -- but minus his humanity. The baseline was the human &amp; divine character,
                                who could be haughty at times, like “I’m above it all,” but he loves humans, he loves
                                people.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>
                                “Subtracting the humanity” sounds like a hard thing to do.
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>JONATHAN:</strong>Well, you think of yourself as detaching from the human race.
                                Humans are . . . not exactly below you, but not quite up to where you are, like a dog or
                                a cat. You still love your dog, you still feed your dog, but you’re not gonna have a
                                conversation with your dog and expect him to answer you. You always know they’re not
                                like you.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>
                                You’ve got a period in Act 3 where you’re fighting alongside the player -- you must have
                                done a lot of fight recording, a lot of sword-swinging type stuff. What was that like?
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>JONATHAN:</strong>
                                 [<em>laughs</em>] I don’t like fighting in games. It’s a hard vocal couple of days.
                                It’d be the same as trying to fight -- not the same exactly, but your whole body gets
                                completely tired. You get very, very worn out. When I was in college, my friends and I
                                had a band; we played one live gig in front of a bunch of people. I was the singer, I
                                sang the whole time, and by the end of it my voice was shot. I hadn’t realized how hard
                                I’d been singing because I was so incredibly nervous. Those fighting days are just like
                                that. You’re so worn out -- to me, it’s incredible. It takes a lot out of you. But we
                                stretched the recording sessions out.
                            </p>
                            <p>You also have different kinds of fighting. “Ok, you just got hit by a big sword.” [<em>
                                vocalizes</em>] “Aaagh.” “Ok, now you got hit by a dagger.” [<em>vocalizes</em>] “Egh.”
                                Different sounds for different things.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>
                                Is it all sort of the same “fight session” recording?
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>JONATHAN:</strong>
                                We’ll have two or three recordings that’ll be two or three hours each of<em>just</em>
                                fighting, because you can’t really do more than that. You’re swinging your sword, you’re
                                blocking, you get hit, you’re hit with a spell. You’re running all over the place.
                                “El’druin!” keeps coming out. Those kinds of things.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>
                                The story of Diablo is pretty dark, it’s fairly bloody, it’s a little brutal, lots of
                                people die -- how do you have fun with something like that?
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>JONATHAN:</strong>
                                I like fantasy, I like science fiction -- I was a D&amp;D player when it was just a
                                little cardboard box with pamphlets in it, and your characters were fighter, thief,
                                wizard, cleric . . . .
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>Oh, man, the Red Box. Classic. Good times.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>JONATHAN:</strong>
                                You had those six-sided, ten, twenty, twelve, four-sided dice; it was a lot of
                                imagination-based fun. I used to play Neverwinter Nights and games like that, Icewind
                                Dale, every Sid Meier’s Civ game. To me, it’s just fun -- it doesn’t really affect me
                                that much.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>
                                I wanted to ask you a question about the craft, too. Do you think that if someone is
                                extremely hard-working and determined, sends out a lot of samples and reels, and really
                                tries, is that enough to get involved in voice acting, or is it more that you have to
                                have a certain voice in order to find your niche?
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>JONATHAN:</strong>There are all kinds of voices in voice acting. Everything. The
                                fact that I have a deep, powerful voice is a leg up for me, and it puts me in a bunch of
                                different niches as an actor. But I also think that the main thing you need to do is not
                                necessarily get yourself out there, but to practice. Like any instrument, you have to
                                learn to play it. Fortunately, I’ve had on-the-job training over the past 5 years. I
                                think that the quality of the performances I’m doing now is a lot better than what I did
                                when I did that first Dormammu character on Dr. Strange. I don’t just rely on the fact
                                that my voice is deep and strong. I really think acting is a craft. Talent
                                <em>helps</em>
                                -- if you have talent for it, that’s great -- but it’s not gonna get you all the way
                                there, nor will just doing a lot get you there. I’d say it’s like 70% craft, 30% talent.
                                Your talent will help your craft, but you really have to keep working at it.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>
                                Jon, thanks so much for your interview.
                            </p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div class="sorNoTable" id="osContainer2">
                    <div>
                        <div class="sorTable">
                            <b class="fancyTitle">David Sobolov - Azmodan</b>
                            <br/>
                            <p>
                                <strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>
                                What got you started down the path toward becoming a voice actor?
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>DAVID:</strong>
                                I was originally a French horn player. I did pit orchestra work, played in small
                                ensembles, and then I started getting into stage acting. About 15 years ago, in
                                Vancouver, an agent saw me, and basically said, “You’ve got a voice that’d be good for
                                villains. You should come do cartoons.” I started booking pretty quickly. In the arts,
                                you have to kind of gravitate toward where they’re willing to pay you. It seemed like
                                that was the most viable path for me. I think a lot of people who are interested in
                                getting into voice acting have no idea how to do it; it just sort of fell into my lap
                                that way.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>
                                How does theatre translate into voice acting?
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>DAVID:</strong>
                                Theatre hugely translates into voice acting. As you’ve seen in Diablo III, you have to
                                be so much bigger than life. Azmodan, in the Black Soulstone cinematic, is larger than
                                any human being could ever be. To even attempt to fit into that in a realistic way, you
                                have to be very theatrical. You want to be huge in your characters, and let [the
                                directors] bring you back if they need to. A lot of people who do what I do come from a
                                theatre background – it really does help a lot.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>
                                Diablo III was in development for several years. How did you stay focused on the
                                character over that period of time?
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>DAVID:</strong>Well, you have to use your skills every time you go back into the
                                studio as a voice actor. They’ll play you a reference of what you did last time, and
                                it’s pretty organic. You remember where you were, emotionally and physically, and you
                                just jump back into the role.
                            </p>
                            <p>The very first scene I worked on years ago was the [Black Soulstone] cinematic. It was
                                out of context; I didn’t quite understand how big of a part I was going to have in the
                                game when I did that cinematic. We worked on those few lines for maybe two-and-a-half or
                                three hours, and I don’t think we even finished it that day, I think we just did some of
                                the lines just to get into the character.
                            </p>
                            <p>I also recall the time you guys took me down to the Blizzard offices in Irvine just to
                                provide “voice” to the movement of the character. They showed me Azmodan’s animations,
                                his feet and big arms, on the screen, and we recorded live, next to the picture. Most of
                                the material was recorded here in LA where the majority of the voice talent is, but it
                                really speaks to the quality of the project that you brought me all the way down to your
                                offices, even though we weren’t doing any dialogue at all, just so you could bring that
                                extra bit of reality to the character.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>
                                So, how do you go about lending your voice to a demon?
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>DAVID:</strong>There’s an acting technique that I was taught by Sanford Meisner,
                                a very famous acting teacher in New York several years ago – it’s to “live truthfully
                                under given imaginary circumstances.” This world doesn’t exist, but you make it exist.
                                If I’m not really Azmodan in that moment, if the people at home don’t believe it,
                                they’re gonna go, “pssh, this guy’s just phoning it in.” It has to actually feel like
                                I’m this huge, amazingly powerful evil guy. So I just kind of get into the space, I get
                                into feeling the power, the size, the weight of the character – all the different
                                aspects that you’d really feel if you were living as that person. It’s a skill you
                                develop over time. But I also think it’s something you can either do or you can’t. You
                                can learn about acting and get performance experience, but you either have to be able to
                                jump into that, or you just can’t. Luckily I’m able to do that, so I keep working.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>
                                Do you remember how long on average you’d spend in the recording studio?
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>DAVID:</strong>
                                Probably 2-3 hours. There might’ve been a four hour session in there somewhere, but this
                                particular character seemed to come, I wouldn’t say “easily,” but it didn’t feel like a
                                huge stretch beyond what I was able to do. And the directors, Andrea Toyias and Andrea
                                Romano, made me feel so comfortable with what I was doing. I never went, “oh, I’ve been
                                here for hours and hours.” The time just flew by.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <img src="http://us.media5.battle.net/cms/gallery/NCOLLJPYJ27U1347387543325.jpg?v=0"
                                     style="float:left;"/>
                                <img src="http://us.media2.battle.net/cms/gallery/EN4ZMU3B6OYY1347387543316.jpg?v=0"
                                     style="float:left;"/>
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>
                                The growls and everything must take a lot out of you.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>DAVID:</strong>
                                You just want to make sure you’re rested, especially if you have a lot of jobs going on.
                                There are some days where I have to just not talk to anybody, and text to save my voice.
                                If I know I’ve got a big week coming up – if I’ve got a video game session while I’m on
                                a couple of animated series – I have to be able to sound like that character did last
                                time, and if my voice is gone, he’s not going to sound very good, is he? Also, I’m
                                pretty tame in my personal life. I’m not going out partying, I don’t smoke, I don’t
                                drink, don’t do drugs, and I just take care of myself.
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>For a guy whose job is to get killed by the player, Azmodan has
                                a
                                <strong>lot</strong>
                                of lines. How did you stay menacing?
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>DAVID:</strong>
                                Well, I think having multiple recording sessions helps. You can only keep that level of
                                intensity up for so many hours, so you do three hours here, three hours there, and when
                                you put it all together, it might be 20 hours of work, but it’s all stuck into one act,
                                so it actually feels more intense than it would otherwise. There’s no way you could keep
                                doing that all day and all night.
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>Azmodan doesn’t really have any lips; how did that influence
                                your delivery?
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>DAVID:</strong>
                                I wasn’t aware that he didn’t have lips until late in the recording process. I think you
                                just have to ignore that, and it’s up to the animators to make it work. I can’t act
                                without my lips – it doesn’t work! We did do some things that made him sound extra fat
                                and a little bit muddy. He was very much [David uses the Azmodan voice]<em>down here
                                like this. Super low, super grumbly</em>. It was an extremely quiet performance, almost
                                whispered. And they blew it up in production to make him sound really huge. That gave
                                Azmodan a level of intimacy he wouldn’t have otherwise . . . a scary intimacy, a level
                                of menace.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>
                                Is it more fun to play a villain?
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>DAVID:</strong>Oh, yeah. It’s fun. I like intelligent villains. It’s what I
                                gravitate to. They
                                <em>always</em>
                                think they’re gonna win. They have so much confidence; there’s not a thought in their
                                mind that they won’t prevail, and they love torturing their enemies. I’m doing something
                                with my hands now like a puppeteer . . . when they get someone in their grasp, there’s
                                an evil sense of play, where they’re in control. It’s very sadistic, I know, but it’s
                                fun to play something so far away from myself.
                            </p>
                            <p>I’ve had sessions where I’ll do something really super evil, and then I’ll just start
                                laughing. It’s the total opposite of who I am; a pretty affable, calm, pleasant person.
                                I’m always playing mean guys in games.
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>Azmodan sounds like he has a tremendous amount of modulation in
                                his voice, a ton of reverb, but you doing the voice without any modulation sounds very
                                similar to the Azmodan I hear in the game. Do you know what was done in production to
                                modify your voice?
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>DAVID:</strong>They put a little reverb on it – that’s about it. I don’t know how
                                this stuff comes out of my face, but it does! I work with guys who do lots of crazy
                                voices, like Dee Bradley Baker, and I just go, “What? That came out of your face? You’re
                                a human being, right?” I have my thing – the super deep, evil thing – and he has his
                                thing. Somebody once told me that I get a lot of video game work because, apparently, my
                                voice is really easy to process. I don’t know why – just the deepness of it.
                            </p>
                            <p>If a character that has a super deep voice has to scream, it’s pretty hard to do. Azmodan
                                never really had to raise his voice very much, because he had so much weight as a
                                character, people would just listen to him. They actually kept bringing me back, like
                                “less emotion, less emotion, more focused emotion.” It was in a very tiny space, like I
                                was always whispering in somebody’s ear.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>
                                I’d never considered that the level or timbre of your voice would affect how easy or
                                difficult it’d be to record you.
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>DAVID:</strong>One of the biggest challenges that I find in video game voice
                                acting is when a super deep-voiced character has to be in a battle. They want so much
                                more intensity – but they want it to be that focused intensity. It sometimes physically
                                can’t happen. Think about human nature; if somebody came up to you with a knife, and you
                                were fighting back, your voice would go higher!
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>
                                Voice acting is something that lot of people are interested in, but many of those same
                                people don’t have the foggiest idea of what goes into it. Do you think that anybody who
                                really works hard and puts a lot of resumes out has the capacity to be a voice actor?
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>DAVID:</strong>Without trying to sounding conceited, the reality is that Joe from
                                accounting can’t walk up to the microphone and be Azmodan. Everybody finds what they’re
                                good at. Dee [Baker] is good at, well, everything, but he’s good at crazy wacky stuff,
                                I’m good at the villainous characters, the dramatic characters – we all have our thing.
                                People have to identify what they’re good at, market themselves, and get tons and tons
                                of practice. It’s a process. I didn’t arrive in LA and have a career handed to me on a
                                silver platter. I had to prove myself.
                            </p>
                            <p>If you just want to start out, you might do improv theatre just to get ready for
                                everything. In a video game session, you often don’t get to read the script in advance –
                                they put it in front of you and they say “go.” I have to give a quality performance from
                                the minute I open my mouth. There’s no second chance. Everything has to be at a certain
                                level; even if you give a great audition, you kind of have to be known in the business
                                for a while before you get the chance to do something as prestigious as a Blizzard game.
                                They’re not just gonna let anybody do it. I guess the answer to your question is that it
                                takes years – years of practice, years of dedication.
                            </p>
                            <p>It’s important to not let anybody squish your dreams, though. If you really believe in
                                yourself and you’re good at what you do, you’ll eventually find your audience.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>
                                One more question! In the game narrative, Azmodan’s dead. By our count, he’s been killed
                                millions of times at this point. Do you think there’s any chance of him – of you –
                                coming back?
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>DAVID:</strong>
                                This is a fantasy world – it doesn’t matter if you’re dead. If you have clever enough
                                writers, anyone can come back to life believably. I’d love to keep going with this
                                character.
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>Thanks so much, David!
                            </p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div class="sorNoTable" id="osContainer3">
                    <div>
                        <div class="sorTable">
                            <b class="fancyTitle">James Hong - Covetous Shen</b>
                            <br/>
                            <p>
                                <strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>
                                Hi, James! I read in your biography that you lived in Hong Kong – what was that like?
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>JAMES:</strong>
                                I was there in Kowloon, educated during grade school from the age of 5 to 9. Everything
                                you do in life adds to your art, and that gave me the sense of adjusting to a whole new
                                world, of the Hong Kong atmosphere, which, as you can imagine, is great. Getting a piece
                                of toast from an old man who used to be hunched over on a street corner near where I
                                stayed – he would make toast for some reason, and you could buy it for a penny. Little
                                images have added to the roles that I play – you have, in your games, a lot of those
                                dark images that are in my memory.
                            </p>
                            <p>Education in the Chinese grade school was great – not the most pleasant thing, but
                                certainly it becomes your background, it enriches who you are. I think everybody should
                                open themselves to travel and experience. Don’t you?
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>
                                Yeah, absolutely. Do you still go back pretty often?
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>JAMES:</strong>
                                Yes, I’ve been back there. When China was just opening up, “taking off their uniforms,”
                                so to say, I was there for months, making “Marco Polo.” This is when China was still
                                China, and not full of hotels. Most of what I saw in Beijing – not most, but half of it
                                is just razed and modernized now. American fast food is all over the place. It’s kind of
                                sad to see all of that go, but, again, that’s become part of my background.
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>Can you tell us a bit about how you got your start with acting
                                in general?
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>JAMES:</strong>
                                The start of my career was in 1953. I got on a quiz show with Groucho Marx. I did some
                                impersonations, including Groucho, Peter Lorrie, Jimmy Stewart. That got out to the
                                United States audience, and I got a huge reaction – they said the 2
                                <sup>nd</sup>
                                biggest fan-mail Groucho ever got on that program. That started the ball rolling. I got
                                an agent, and my first role was in
                                <em>Soldier of Fortune</em>
                                with Clark Gable.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>
                                You’ve had an amazingly broad career since then. You’ve done a lot of film and
                                animation; I know you personally from<em>Mulan</em>,<em>Kung Fu Panda</em>,<em>Big
                                Trouble [in Little China]</em>, and you’ve started doing video games.
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>JAMES:</strong>I’d like to see if one of these days if I could put my name in the
                                almanac as the actor with the most character roles. I think I hold that record, though
                                I’m not sure.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>
                                If you don’t hold that record, you’re definitely in the running. Yeah, you should see
                                about that.
                            </p>
                            <p>So, I was curious – with all the film and animation work in your background, do you do
                                anything different to prepare for working on a video game?
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>JAMES:</strong>
                                A little bit. Video games are a separate entity – the biggest entertainment industry of
                                late. So you do have to approach it differently, certainly differently from an on-camera
                                job. On camera, you have to fuss around with wardrobe, makeup, get into character – I
                                think of all the work I did for “Big Trouble in Little China,” for Lo Pan, with
                                different makeup, months studying the role. Now, with video games, you don’t have all
                                that trouble getting into a role physically, but it’s a different approach – you read
                                the script, study the character, and find out what the<em>purpose</em>of the character
                                is, his history and mission, what he’s trying to accomplish, and then you go in and do
                                the voice, and from that point the voice director takes over. You can go in in your
                                pajamas and do the lines, and it’s okay.
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>Tell us about your time in the studio recording for Covetous
                                Shen on Diablo III.
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                <strong>JAMES:</strong>
                                We went down to the LA studio – it was always the same studio, I remember it well.
                                Andrea Toyias was always behind the booth giving me direction, and she’s a great voice
                                director. I remember that I had to do a LOT of takes. The director was very meticulous –
                                it was one try after another until we nailed it down, because I didn’t exactly have a
                                picture of what was happening in the game. I had a vague idea, but have to I rely on the
                                director to guide me through the scene with clues.
                            </p>
                            <p>I remember goofing around and doing voices from
                                <em>Big Trouble</em>
                                to make everybody laugh, and then moving right back into the game voice. One has to have
                                some fun with it, obviously. I think you see that; hopefully the player gets to see the
                                sense of humor we put into Covetous Shen.
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>BLIZZARD:</strong>I think they absolutely have. You’ve got what’s probably the
                                quirkiest voice in the game – it’s super idiosyncratic, and I don’t think anyone else
                                sounds like you. When you did the voice for Shen, did you do any ad-libbing, or was that
                                entirely pre-planned?
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>JAMES</strong>: I tried to do some ad-libs. I kind of snuck it up on them – I’d
                                do a few lines that Andrea thought would be good for the game, and then throw in a few
                                ad-libs, whether it’s a laugh or a quirky comment that I think Covetous might do,
                                because he’s a sneaky little character, you know? He kind of gets under your skin one
                                way or another. By the time I’ve done a voice three or four times, I know what I want
                                the player to feel, and that’s the whole gist of the game. That’s the craft with games –
                                just through your voice, to draw the player into a situation that he possibly has not
                                thought about, and lead him in a direction to solve problems.
                            </p>
                            <center>
                                <img src="http://us.media5.battle.net/cms/gallery/IDBUN0LSDOHM1347387544212.jpg?v=0"/>
                                <img src="http://us.media1.battle.net/cms/gallery/K5EZR46RPZCA1347387543385.jpg?v=1"/>
                            </center>
                            <p><strong>BLIZZARD</strong>: Your character in Diablo III is very wise, but, as you pointed
                                out, he’s also a bit silly, kind of a trickster-style character. How do you balance
                                those two qualities? They seem almost like they’d be a little opposed.
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>JAMES</strong>: In a way, it’s tough; in a way it’s not. I’m that kind of person
                                – I love to poke fun and stimulate other people to action. I hate the status quo. With
                                food, like Covetous, I like to taste different things. When I sit down to a dinner, I
                                try to get other people to order something that I like too, so I can eat off of their
                                plate. When I eat Chinese food, I order more dishes than I can possibly eat so that I
                                can try each one of them. In that sense, Covetous is not too different from the real
                                James Hong – we’re just out to grab some fun out of life.
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>BLIZZARD</strong>: Do you remember how long your recording sessions were? Were
                                they 4-hour long marathon sessions, or shorter sessions?
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>JAMES</strong>: They averaged between 1 and 2 hours – sometimes a little longer,
                                sometimes shorter. I like variety, and I can only be really good in a period of 2 hours.
                                After that, I start fading. I worked with Frank Sinatra on a film called<em>Never So
                                    Few</em>. I’ll always remember that, because we’d rehearse a little bit – Frank
                                didn’t like to rehearse too much – and then when the camera was ready, Frank shouted, [
                                <em>imitating Sinatra perfectly</em>] “All right, you got one take, and that’s it!”
                                Everybody’s trembling and shaking because they’ve gotta get things perfect in one take.
                                That’s what Frank did – he was a great one-taker.
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>BLIZZARD</strong>: Knowing that as a series, Diablo can be a bit on the dark side
                                – hacking up zombies, violence, etc. – how do you keep it fun or light? How do you have
                                a good time with it?
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>JAMES</strong>: It’s a very important question – throughout my career, I’ve done
                                some ‘heavy’ roles, serious roles in
                                <em>Chinatown</em>
                                and so forth. It’s very important that you get into doing a voice, making a game work
                                for yourself and for players, but once you’re through acting – or through playing –
                                you’ve really gotta divorce yourself from [it], and find your own self again. I find
                                myself, when I’ve done a role, naturally repeating lines over in my head as I’m driving
                                home – and I’ve got to get out of that, get back to reality and my real relationship
                                with people and what I’m doing. Do something else – play baseball, go dancing – and get
                                back into your real life. I don’t know how else to put it, but it’s very important to
                                keep a yin and yang balance.
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>BLIZZARD</strong>: What was the most fun part of portraying Covetous Shen?
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>JAMES</strong>: He’s a jeweler. He makes jewelry. He takes bits of gems and makes
                                a better whole out of them, and crafts for the player. Though he would like to find a
                                particular gem for himself – he is very greedy and very selfish in a sense – in the
                                meantime, he does a great service, helping the player add gems to weapons or equipment.
                                It gave me a thrill to know that I’m actually helping the player. Hopefully that comes
                                through in my role.
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>BLIZZARD</strong>: Do you think there's more to Covetous? That maybe he’s a
                                deity? Do you think he’s just messing with the player?
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>JAMES</strong>: I like to think that he’s a deity of some kind. To me, he’s
                                probably an outcast among the deities, who was thrown onto [Sanctuary] because he was
                                naughty. Now, he’s just doing his deeds. He’s a scrounger. He looks for little pieces of
                                jewelry, and tries to make something out of everything that he finds. He looks like a
                                bag man, and he’s very sarcastic, but his knowledge is great. So there’s something
                                behind that knowledge – how he got it, and how he became a maker of jewels is a big
                                mystery.
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>BLIZZARD</strong>: One thing that I hear quite a lot from players of Blizzard
                                games is a general interest in the craft of voice acting, so I wanted to ask you about
                                that. Do you think that it’s possible for anybody who’s determined and hardworking
                                enough to get into acting or animation for games, or do you think that you need to have
                                a certain talent, that your voice has to sound a certain way or you have to meet a
                                particular niche, a voice that people identify with a certain build or nationality?
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>JAMES</strong>: I think it’s both. How I more or less got into this is that I
                                used to talk to myself a lot, as a lonely child, mimicking this and that, and that
                                became sort of the training grounds for being a voice actor. I never thought of it as
                                that, but it became very valuable. Changing their voice is something most young people
                                do, whether in their childhood or later in life. You simply take that innate talent and
                                train it. There are voiceover teachers here in Hollywood, because doing voice work is a
                                different craft than just acting on stage. When you do a voiceover, you’re sitting in
                                that chair alone with a microphone – that’s your whole surrounding. You have nothing
                                else but your innate talent and imagination to rely on. You have to know how to apply
                                your training, your surroundings, your spirit, your soul, and what your imagination can
                                create. Some people that I’ve heard do voices, I sit there and I’m amazed, totally
                                amazed by what they can do. There are so many good actors around. There’s no easy way to
                                do it – it’s a crowded field – but once you get into it, and directors and producers
                                come to rely on you, you’re gonna get a lot of work, whether it’s doing characters or
                                just doing announcing.
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>BLIZZARD</strong>: Are you into jewelry at all, or was that just acting?
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>JAMES</strong>: Into actual jewelry, no, into crafting, yes. As a young child, I
                                loved woodwork, metalwork, making go-carts. I still love to create things and draw. As
                                far as helping the player as Covetous Shen . . . I do wish I’d get a tip from time to
                                time. At the least, I hope the players can give me a ‘thank you.’ Maybe they can go to
                                my
                                <a href="http://www.facebook.com/JamesHongPage">Facebook page</a>
                                and thank me for showing them a good time as Covetous Shen. It’s a fun page.
                            </p>
                            <p><strong>BLIZZARD</strong>: I know you’re really busy; thanks for spending all this time
                                talking with us, James!
                            </p>
                        </div>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <p>
                    <script language="javascript">
                        function osTabSelect(thisElement, divNum) {
                            document.getElementsByClassName("goose")[0].className = "duck";
                            thisElement.className = "goose";
                            document.getElementById("osContentDiv").innerHTML = document.getElementById("osContainer" + divNum).innerHTML;
                        }
                    </script>
                    <style type="text/css">
                        #blog .table2 {
                            margin: 0 auto;
                        }

                        #blog .table2 th div {
                            font-family: Georgia, "Times New Roman", Times, serif;
                            font-size: 12px;
                            color: #D96500;
                            -moz-border-radius: 4px;
                            -webkit-border-radius: 4px;
                            border-radius: 4px;
                            border-bottom-left-radius: 0;
                            border-bottom-right-radius: 0;
                            -moz-box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                            -webkit-box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                            box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                            border: 1px solid #483d2b;
                            border-bottom-width: 0px;
                            float: left;
                            cursor: pointer;
                        }

                        #blog .table2 th div:hover {
                            color: #FC9;
                            text-decoration: underline
                        }

                        .duck {
                            padding: 7px 14px 2px 14px;
                            margin-top: 5px
                        }

                        .goose {
                            padding: 7px 14px 7px 14px;
                            margin-top: 0px
                        }

                        .fancyTitle {
                            font-family: Georgia, "Times New Roman", Times, serif;
                            font-size: 15px;
                            color: #efc9a0;
                        }

                        .sorTable {
                            -moz-border-radius: 4px;
                            -webkit-border-radius: 4px;
                            border-radius: 4px;
                            -moz-box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                            -webkit-box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                            box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                            border: 1px solid #483d2b;
                            padding: 20px;
                            line-height: 1.5em;
                            background-color: #12110f;
                            background-position: top right;
                            background-repeat: no-repeat;
                            margin-bottom: 3px;
                        }

                        .sorTable i {
                            font-size: 10px;
                            color: #C96;
                        }

                        .sorTable img {
                            -moz-border-radius: 4px;
                            -webkit-border-radius: 4px;
                            border-radius: 4px;
                            -moz-box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                            -webkit-box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                            box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                            padding: 1px;
                            border: 1px solid #483d2b;
                            margin: 4px 0px 12px 7px;
                        }

                        .sorNoTable {
                            display: none;
                        }</style>
                </p>
            </div>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="text">Battle.net SMS Protect: Have You Heard?</title>
        <published>2012-09-13T17:00:00.000Z</published>
        <updated>2012-09-12T22:25:50.643Z</updated>
        <id>7206800</id>
        <link href="http://us.battle.net//d3/en/blog/7206800"/>
        <summary type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>
                    <span style="font-size: 12px; ">You’ve probably heard about the benefits of using a Battle.net
                        Authenticator or Battle.net Mobile Authenticator app by now. But did you know that a few months
                        ago, we introduced a new, optional security measure called 
                    </span>
                    <strong style="font-size: 12px; ">Battle.net SMS Protect</strong>
                    <span style="font-size: 12px; "> that works in tandem with the Authenticator to help safeguard your
                        account?</span> 
                </p>
            </div>
        </summary>
        <content type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>You’ve probably heard about the benefits of using a Battle.net Authenticator or Battle.net Mobile
                    Authenticator app by now. But did you know that a few months ago, we introduced a new, optional
                    security measure called
                    <strong>Battle.net SMS Protect</strong>
                    that works in tandem with the Authenticator to help safeguard your account?
                </p>
                <p>Battle.net SMS Protect lets you perform certain account actions, such as removing your Authenticator
                    from your mobile phone, and can be set up to provide you with account-activity notifications. All
                    you need is a supported text-enabled cell phone to get started.
                </p>
                <p>What can Battle.net SMS Protect do for you?</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Unlock your Battle.net account</li>
                    <li>Remove a damaged or lost Authenticator</li>
                    <li>Recover your account name</li>
                    <li>Reset your password</li>
                </ul>
                <p>In addition, you can turn on alerts to have text messages sent directly to your phone notifying you
                    of certain kinds of account activity, such as password changes and security feature additions or
                    removals.
                </p>
                <p>These text messages are a free* and easy way to help protect your account from unauthorized access
                    and changes.
                </p>
                <p>Remember, you can help further safeguard your Battle.net account by never sharing your password,
                    using unique passwords on each site you visit, and being aware of potential email and phishing
                    scams.
                </p>
                <p>For more information on Battle.net SMS Protect and instructions on how to set it up, visit the
                    Battle.net SMS Protect<a href="http://battle.net/support/article/3300033" target="_blank">FAQ</a>.  
                </p>
                <p style="text-align: center; ">
                    <iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315"
                            src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/jkU6BpbEnt0" width="560"/>
                </p>
                <p>We also encourage you to learn more about what you can do to help safeguard your account by reviewing
                    the various resources available on our<a href="http://battle.net/security/checklist"
                                                             target="_blank">security checklist</a>.
                </p>
                <p>
                    <em>*Your phone carrier's standard rate for received text messages may apply.</em>
                </p>
            </div>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="text">Patch 1.0.5 Sneak Peek</title>
        <published>2012-09-13T14:00:00.000Z</published>
        <updated>2012-09-13T03:08:01.008Z</updated>
        <id>7155880</id>
        <link href="http://us.battle.net//d3/en/blog/7155880"/>
        <summary type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>
                    <span style="font-size: 12px; ">We’ll have articles in the coming days providing all the details on
                        the upcoming patch, but we wanted to give you a sneak peek at what major features to expect.
                    </span>
                </p>
            </div>
        </summary>
        <content type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>We’ll have articles in the coming days providing all the details on the upcoming patch, but we wanted
                    to give you a sneak peek at what major features to expect.
                    <br/>
                     
                </p>
                <p style="margin-left: 40px; ">
                    <strong>Defensive Skill Changes</strong>
                    <br/>
                    In our eternal quest to promote build diversity; we’ll be making changes to defensive skills across
                    the board while simultaneously reducing incoming damage. The net result is a survivability buff for
                    players, and an increase in build options as defensive abilities become less “mandatory.”
                    <br/>
                    <br/>
                    <strong>New Event: Infernal Machine</strong>
                    <br/>
                    The Infernal Machine is a device that will allow level-60 players to battle “uber” versions of some
                    of Sanctuary’s most nefarious bosses. While the rewards for defeating these bosses will be great,
                    some assembly is required.
                    <br/>
                    <br/>
                    <strong>New System: Monster Power</strong>
                    <br/>
                    Similar to the “Players 8” command in Diablo II, the Monster Power system is designed to give
                    players more control over how challenging enemies are in each difficulty.
                </p>
                <p>
                    <br/>
                    This and more is coming in Patch 1.0.5! Stay tuned for all the gory details.
                </p>
                <style type="text/css">
                    #blog .detail img {
                        -moz-border-radius: 4px;
                        -webkit-border-radius: 4px;
                        border-radius: 4px;
                        -moz-box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                        -webkit-box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                        box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                        border: 1px solid #372511;
                        max-width: 570px !important;
                        padding: 1px;
                    }

                    #blog .detail #center {
                        width: 590px;
                        margin: 0px auto;
                    }

                    #blog .divider-down {
                        width: 100%;
                        height: 18px;
                        background: url('http://us.media3.battle.net/cms/gallery/KKZW0YDVPDT91334191716743.png?v=2') center center no-repeat;
                    }

                    #blog .divider-up {
                        width: 100%;
                        height: 18px;
                        background: url('http://us.media1.battle.net/cms/gallery/MO010OF9ESV11334191716770.png?v=2') center center no-repeat;
                    }</style>
            </div>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="text">Final Issue of Sword of Justice Now Available</title>
        <published>2012-09-07T01:00:00.000Z</published>
        <updated>2012-09-07T00:48:59.366Z</updated>
        <id>7155883</id>
        <link href="http://us.battle.net//d3/en/blog/7155883"/>
        <summary type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>The fifth and final issue of
                    <em>
                        <strong>Diablo: Sword of Justice</strong>
                    </em>
                    is now available in stores and online!
                </p>
                <p> </p>
            </div>
        </summary>
        <content type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>From the explosive team of Aaron Williams (<em>North 40</em>) and famed French artist Joseph Lacroix
                    (<em>L'Encyclopédie du mal</em>) comes
                    <strong>
                        <em>Diablo: Sword of Justice</em>
                    </strong>
                    .
                </p>
                <p>A horrific plague of madness is spreading throughout the Dreadlands, transforming its victims into
                    bloodthirsty savages. The only hope of stopping the affliction before it consumes humanity may lie
                    with Jacob, a wanted fugitive whose destiny is bound up with Archangel Tyrael's legendary Sword of
                    Justice.
                </p>
                <p>In this final issue, Jacob and the wizard Shanar gain a new ally in their quest to save Staalbreak.
                    Their journey takes them to the depths of the demonic infestation in the ruins of Mount Arreat.
                </p>
                <p style="text-align: center; ">
                    <a class="lightbox"
                       href="http://us.media5.battle.net/cms/gallery/GVJOMF8IDA0Y1346978150958.jpg?v=1">
                        <img alt="" src="http://us.media1.battle.net/cms/gallery/YX1N7UC15U021346978129639.jpg?v=1"
                             style="width: 600px; height: 250px; "/>
                    </a>
                </p>
                <p style="text-align: center; ">
                    <a class="lightbox"
                       href="http://us.media1.battle.net/cms/gallery/GZ0419LHOMF41346978104055.jpg?v=1">
                        <img alt="" src="http://us.media3.battle.net/cms/gallery/69OEOOYYNGN41346978078720.jpg?v=1"
                             style="width: 600px; height: 250px; "/>
                    </a>
                </p>
                <p>Pick up a copy to see how this series ends, as Staalbreak's future is in Jacob's hands:</p>
                <p>
                    <a href="https://read.dccomics.com/comixology/#" target="_blank">DC Comics on Comixology</a>
                    <br/>
                    <a href="http://www.comicshoplocator.com/" target="_blank">Local Comic Retailers</a>
                </p>
                <p> </p>
                <style type="text/css">
                    #blog .detail #center {
                        width: 590px;
                        margin: 0px auto;
                    }

                    #blog .divider-down {
                        width: 100%;
                        height: 18px;
                        background: url('http://us.media3.battle.net/cms/gallery/KKZW0YDVPDT91334191716743.png?v=2') center center no-repeat;
                    }

                    #blog .divider-up {
                        width: 100%;
                        height: 18px;
                        background: url('http://us.media1.battle.net/cms/gallery/MO010OF9ESV11334191716770.png?v=2') center center no-repeat;
                    }

                    #blog .detail div.ctextheadline {
                        position: relative;
                        display: block;
                        text-decoration: none;
                        line-height: 1 !important;
                        font-family: Georgia !important;
                        margin-left: 3px;
                    }

                    #blog .detail div.ctextheadline h1 {
                        position: absolute;
                        top: 17px;
                        left: 30px;
                        color: #FFBF55 !important;
                        font-size: 23px !important;
                    }

                    #blog .detail div.cteaser, #blog .detail img, #blog .detail div.cteaserg {
                        -moz-border-radius: 4px;
                        -webkit-border-radius: 4px;
                        border-radius: 4px;
                        -moz-box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                        -webkit-box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                        box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                        border: 1px solid #372511;
                        padding: 1px;
                    }

                    #blog .detail div.cteaser, #blog .detail div.cteaserg {
                        width: 285px;
                        height: 144px;
                        margin: 8px 3px 0px 3px;
                        padding-top: 5px;
                        background-color: #1D100A;
                        float: left;
                    }

                    #blog .detail div.cteaser:hover {
                        border: 1px solid #CD9000;
                        background-color: #40200d;
                    }

                    #blog .detail .cteaser a.cteaserimg, #blog .detail .cteaserg div.cteaserimg {
                        display: block;
                        width: 125px;
                        height: 140px;
                        text-align: center;
                        float: left;
                    }

                    #blog .detail .cteaser a.cteaserimg img, #blog .detail .cteaserg div.cteaserimg img {
                        -moz-border-radius: 10px;
                        -webkit-border-radius: 10px;
                        border-radius: 10px;
                        -moz-box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                        -webkit-box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                        box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                        border: 1px solid #1D100A;
                        vertical-align: middle;
                        width: 109px;
                        height: 109px;
                        margin-top: 10px;
                        padding: 1px;
                    }

                    #blog .detail .cteaser a.cteasersummary, #blog .detail .cteaserg div.cteasersummary {
                        display: block;
                        padding-right: 3px;
                        line-height: 1.4 !important;
                        width: 157px;
                        height: 140px;
                        float: left;
                    }

                    #blog .detail .cteaser a.cteasersummary span.headline, #blog .detail .cteaserg div.cteasersummary span.headline {
                        color: #d19205 !important;
                        font-size: 17px !important;
                        text-weight: bold !important;
                    }

                    #blog .detail .cteaser a.cteasersummary span.summarytext, #blog .detail .cteaserg div.cteasersummary span.summarytext {
                        color: #ad8460 !important;
                        font-size: 12px !important;
                    }

                    .top-list tr:nth-child(2) td {
                        color: #F0E29A;
                        background-color: transparent;
                    }

                    .top-list-interior table tbody tr td {
                        background-color: none !important;
                        color: #EFC9A0 !important;
                        font-weight: normal !important;
                        vertical-align: top;
                    }

                    .top-list-interior table tbody tr:hover td {
                        color: #fff !important;
                    }

                    #blog .detail a img:hover {
                        border: 1px solid #CD9000;
                    }</style>
                <style type="text/css">
                    .pullquote:before {
                        content: "\201C" attr(title) "\201D";
                        font-size: 1.2em;
                        display: block;
                        float: right;
                        width: 8em;
                        margin: 0.25em 1em 0.5em 0;
                        padding: 1em;
                    }</style>
            </div>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="text">Developer Journal: Crowd Control Changes</title>
        <published>2012-09-05T16:00:00.000Z</published>
        <updated>2012-09-05T17:19:24.966Z</updated>
        <id>7100052</id>
        <link href="http://us.battle.net//d3/en/blog/7100052"/>
        <summary type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>
                    <span style="font-size: 12px; ">As a team, we're not really a fan of the way CC skills become less
                        powerful as a result of diminishing effects. While we know that a system to limit CC was
                        required to add challenge at higher difficulties, we've wanted to improve CC for some time now.
                        We had bigger fish to fry first (like adding the Paragon System and improving Legendary items),
                        so we made a note to revisit CC effects in patch 1.0.5. Here's our plan. 
                    </span>
                </p>
            </div>
        </summary>
        <content type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>Shortly after Diablo III launched, I remember watching Jay play his barbarian. He was having a blast,
                    killing monsters left and right, but something was bothering him. He was annoyed because Ground
                    Stomp -- one of his favorite abilities -- got worse as he progressed to higher difficulty levels,
                    and that his character felt weaker despite having better gear and more stat points.
                </p>
                <p>We all agreed that the game needed to get harder at higher difficulty levels, but Jay didn't like
                    this<em>particular way </em>that it was getting harder. Specifically, he didn't like that we
                    diminished crowd control (CC) effects.  We had discussed CC effects many times during development,
                    and we felt the system we had got the job done, but Jay felt we could do better.
                </p>
                <p>Before release, we'd designed the game so that CC skills would have diminished durations at higher
                    difficulties -- for example, most CC skills have their effectiveness reduced by 65% in Hell and
                    Inferno. Jay has never been a fan of the way Ground Stomp and other CC skills become less powerful
                    as a result of diminishing effects, but he also knew that a system to limit CC was required to add
                    challenge at higher difficulties.  While we've wanted to improve CC for some time now, we had bigger
                    fish to fry first (like adding the Paragon System and improving Legendary items), so we made a note
                    to revisit CC effects in a future patch.
                    <br/>
                     
                </p>
                <div class="ctextheadline">
                    <img src="http://us.media2.battle.net/cms/content_folder_media/68QM1Z2BEQ7P1346202513108.jpg?v=0"
                         style="width: 590px; height: 56px; "/>
                    <h1>
                        Why We Reduce CC
                    </h1>
                </div>
                <p>Fast forward to present day as we prepare for patch 1.0.5.  Before I talk about what we're doing to
                    buff CC skills while still allowing the game to get harder, first, let's go over some of the reasons
                    why we diminish the effects of CC in Diablo III:
                </p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Monsters need time to do their thing to threaten you.</li>
                    <li>While infinite CC rotations can feel make players feel awesome, it's fleeting. If CC becomes too
                        powerful, it can trivialize most major mechanics and the game can become boring.
                    </li>
                    <li>Players in co-op have the potential to synchronize CC.</li>
                </ul>
                <p>Of course, there are side effects to reducing CC to increase difficulty. One of the bigger issues
                    we've seen is that, when it comes to mitigating incoming damage, CC skills rarely hold up against
                    other options as you progress through Nightmare, Hell, and Inferno. While a skill like Ground Stomp
                    mitigates damage, let's you control the battlefield, and is really fun to use, the duration
                    reduction at higher difficulties is really noticeable, making the skill far less effective. Ignore
                    Pain, on the other hand, mitigates damage by reducing how much of it you take, regardless of
                    difficulty level. It may not be as exciting to trigger, but it's more reliable in those later levels
                    since its power isn't diminished.
                </p>
                <p>The following graphs show a few examples of how CC skills become less widely used as players progress
                    from levels 25, 47, and 59 
                    <strong>*</strong>
                    (the levels you're likely to be at Act III Normal, Act III Nightmare, and Act III Hell):
                </p>
                <p style="text-align: center; ">
                    <a class="lightbox"
                       href="http://us.media4.battle.net/cms/content_folder_media/QPH4B2VJSTIL1346800728537.jpg?v=0">
                        <img alt=""
                             src="http://us.media4.battle.net/cms/content_folder_media/QPH4B2VJSTIL1346800728537.jpg?v=0"
                             style="width: 250px; height: 140px; "/>
                    </a>
                    <a class="lightbox"
                       href="http://us.media3.battle.net/cms/content_folder_media/PNRQ1DO26FGR1346800728537.jpg?v=0">
                        <img alt=""
                             src="http://us.media3.battle.net/cms/content_folder_media/PNRQ1DO26FGR1346800728537.jpg?v=0"
                             style="width: 250px; height: 140px; margin-left: 15px; margin-right: 15px; "/>
                    </a>
                </p>
                <p style="text-align: center; ">
                    <a class="lightbox"
                       href="http://us.media2.battle.net/cms/content_folder_media/BMCZ1QGXIW0Q1346800728528.jpg?v=0">
                        <img alt=""
                             src="http://us.media2.battle.net/cms/content_folder_media/BMCZ1QGXIW0Q1346800728528.jpg?v=0"
                             style="width: 250px; height: 140px; "/>
                    </a>
                </p>
                <p>It's no surprise that as the effectiveness of a CC skill starts to diminish, its relative value
                    (especially against skills that provide self-buffs) starts to diminish as well. This can make you
                    feel less powerful as a player, but it also starts to push people into a narrower set of builds.
                    After all, if one skill's power depreciates over time and another skill's power doesn't, the skill
                    that retains its power can become much more appealing.
                </p>
                <p>
                    <span style="font-size: 12px; text-align: center; ">
                        <strong style="font-size: 10px; ">*</strong>
                    </span>
                    <em style="font-size: 10px; text-align: center; ">T
                        <span style="font-size: 11px; ">hese graphs illustrate the general trend of how, as players
                            level up, CC skills become less popular, while skills that provide self-buffs become more
                            popular. We opted to not include level 60 data in these graphs because there are many builds
                            in Inferno that use CC skills successfully (for example, Frost Nova with Critical Mass).
                            While we think these synergy-based builds are awesome, they’re still outliers and would
                            ultimately skew the graph data from the overall trend.
                        </span>
                    </em>
                    <span style="font-size: 12px; text-align: center; "> </span>
                    <span style="font-size: 12px; "> </span>
                    <span style="font-size: 12px; "> </span>
                    <span style="font-size: 12px; "> </span> 
                    <br/>
                     
                </p>
                <div class="ctextheadline">
                    <img src="http://us.media1.battle.net/cms/content_folder_media/XGMM6ZO353Q61346202513002.jpg?v=0"
                         style="width: 590px; height: 56px; "/>
                    <h1>
                        Trial and Error
                    </h1>
                </div>
                <p>Crowd controlling monsters is not only tactically valuable, but we think it's really fun, too. Our
                    goal was to recapture that feeling in the higher difficulties. We wanted players to feel strong and
                    heroic when using their CC skills, no matter what level they are, and we came up with a few ideas on
                    how to accomplish that.
                </p>
                <div class="divider-up">
                     
                </div>
                <p>
                    <strong>Idea #1: Reduce the Duration of CC effects in Co-Op Games</strong>
                    <br/>
                    The first solution we came up with was to reduce the duration of CC effects in co-op games only, and
                    allow full durations in single-player. While this would provide a great experience for solo players
                    and help prevent the issue of infinite CC rotations in group play, the obvious downside is that CC
                    skills would still feel weak in co-op games.
                </p>
                <p>There are already a few mechanics (such as On Kill triggers) that discourage players from teaming up
                    with their friends, and we don’t want to pile on "my CC is less effective" as yet another reason to
                    avoid co-op. So, we tossed that idea out and went back to the drawing board.
                </p>
                <p>
                    <strong>Idea # 2: Make Diminishing Effects Not as Strong</strong>
                    <br/>
                    We also discussed making all CC effects shorter from the start, but make them not diminish (this
                    would apply for both single-player and co-op games).  For example, we talked about making Ground
                    Stomp always last for 2 seconds, even when you first get it at level 1.  Sure, it's not as good at
                    first, but at least it doesn't get worse with time.
                </p>
                <p>Of course, this means that we’d have to make CC less powerful across the board. Although it solves
                    the original problem of CC skills feeling weaker over time, it creates the new problem of "my CC
                    skills never feel powerful," which is arguably worse.
                </p>
                <p>
                    <strong>Idea #3: Diminishing Returns</strong>
                    <br/>
                    Another idea we considered was implementing diminishing returns the way World of Warcraft does. So,
                    your first stun gets full duration, the second stun is cut in half, the third stun is cut by 75%,
                    and for the fourth stun and beyond you get "IMMUNE." 
                </p>
                <p>While this works for WoW, it just doesn't seem like a good fit for Diablo III. Not only does it feel
                    really weird to get an "IMMUNE" message, but it also puts a lot of limitations on you in co-op games
                    when the order in which you and your teammate use CC can matter a great deal. 
                </p>
                <p>Let's say you have a 5 second stun and your partner has a 1.5 second stun.  If you go first, the
                    monster is stunned for 5 + 0.75 seconds = 5.75 seconds total.  If your partner goes first, the
                    monster is stunned for 1.5 + 2.5 seconds = 4 seconds total.  That seems like more micromanagement
                    than we want to place in a fast-paced action game like Diablo III.  
                </p>
                <p>Additionally, there are currently a few methods of CC which are already very potent.  For example,
                    certain wizard and monk builds can maintain extremely heavy CC on enemies. As we examined CC, we
                    realized we wanted to make CC skills feel good on their own, while still allowing these dedicated
                    builds and combinations to be successful. In effect, we want to buff the baseline usage without
                    hurting the players who have figured out certain potent combinations (though in the big picture we
                    are still keeping an eye on that).  This was yet another reason not to adopt the WoW diminishing
                    returns system.
                </p>
                <div class="divider-down">
                     
                </div>
                <p>As you can see, every one of the solutions we discussed had a pretty noticeable downside, and we were
                    kind of left hanging.  We went over the reasons together and Jay basically said, "I know WHY we
                    reduce the durations, but I still don't like it. Keep working on it."
                </p>
                <p> </p>
                <div class="ctextheadline">
                    <img src="http://us.media2.battle.net/cms/content_folder_media/PXUGPR27D8TR1346202513000.jpg?v=0"
                         style="width: 590px; height: 56px; "/>
                    <h1>
                        Developers, Assemble!
                    </h1>
                </div>
                <p>As we started to wrap up development for patch 1.0.4, I decided to get a fresh perspective on the
                    situation and hit up some designers on World of Warcraft and StarCraft II.  One of the great things
                    about working at Blizzard is being able to tap the creativity of other development teams, while
                    still being able to do what is right for the Diablo franchise. Although they work on a different
                    game, many of the designers around the company have been playing the heck out of Diablo III, and I
                    figured they would be able to offer me some deeper insight into what they thought worked and what
                    didn't.
                </p>
                <p>After tossing out ideas for a while, we had a small epiphany:
                    <em>What if we used diminishing returns, but developed a different set of rules for Diablo III?</em>
                </p>
                <p>What if monsters just never went immune? And what if, instead of reduced % durations, the durations
                    were reduced based on the length of the CC, so that it didn’t matter which order the CC effects were
                    applied when playing co-op?
                </p>
                <p>Here's the system we arrived at:</p>
                <p>
                    <strong>How It Works:</strong>
                </p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Monsters have a "CC resistance" that is stored on a per-monster basis.</li>
                    <li>The CC resistance starts at 0%.  For every 1 second CC that is applied to the monster, the
                        monster receives 10% CC resistance.
                    </li>
                    <li>Monsters lose 10% of their CC resistance every second that they are not CC’d.</li>
                    <li>Elite monster CC resistance is capped at the current reduction values already active for
                        Elites.  In other words, CC resistance on most Elite monsters is capped to:
                        <ul style="margin-left: 40px; ">
                            <li>35% in Normal</li>
                            <li>50% in Nightmare</li>
                            <li>65% in Hell</li>
                            <li>65% in Inferno</li>
                        </ul>
                    </li>
                </ul>
                <p>
                    <strong>What This Means For the Player:</strong>
                </p>
                <ul>
                    <li>From a high level, diminishing returns are applied on consecutive stuns to reduce their
                        effectiveness.
                    </li>
                    <li>You will never get an "Immune" message due to diminishing returns.</li>
                    <li>Diminishing returns on Elite monsters cap out at the same values that are currently applied to
                        Elite reductions.
                        <ul>
                            <li>As previous mentioned, this means that near-infinite CC strategies will still work. 
                                We're okay with these strategies remaining viable, as we love how powerful it makes
                                players feel. (That said, we will continue to keep an eye on these strategies and may
                                make some changes in the future if we feel it will be better for the health of the
                                game.)
                            </li>
                        </ul>
                    </li>
                    <li>If two players are in a co-op game, the order in which they apply their stuns doesn't generally
                        matter, so you shouldn't feel totally "screwed over" by the other person applying their stun
                        before yours.
                    </li>
                    <li>A character using only the occasional CC every 10-15 seconds will always get the full duration
                        in all difficulty levels.
                    </li>
                </ul>
                <p> </p>
                <div class="ctextheadline">
                    <img src="http://us.media4.battle.net/cms/content_folder_media/GYIG86CD1S091346202513358.jpg?v=0"
                         style="width: 590px; height: 56px; "/>
                    <h1>
                        A Free Demonstration
                    </h1>
                </div>
                <p>Let's provide some examples to show how this new system can play out in real scenarios.</p>
                <p>
                    <strong>Example 1:</strong>
                </p>
                <ol>
                    <li>A wizard freezes an Elite monster in Inferno difficulty for three seconds using Frost Nova. The
                        monster is frozen for the full 3 seconds and now has 30% CC resistance (+10% resistance per
                        second for 3 seconds = 30% CC resistance).
                    </li>
                    <li>The moment the freeze ends, a witch doctor casts Horrify which fears the monster for 4
                        seconds. Since the monster has 30% CC resistance, it’s actually only feared for 2.8 seconds
                        (4 seconds * 70% CC effectiveness = 2.8 seconds). The monster now has 58% CC resistance (30%
                        from the first 3 second freeze + 28% from the 2.8 second fear).
                    </li>
                    <li>After 5.8 seconds (freeze + fear duration), the monster is no longer CC’d. Suppose nothing
                        happens for 5 seconds.  During this time, the monster loses 50% of its CC resistance and is now
                        at 8% CC resistance (58% - 50% = 8% CC resistance).
                    </li>
                    <li>A monk casts Blinding Flash, applying a 3 second blind.  The monster is blinded for 2.76 seconds
                        (8% CC resistance off of 3 seconds) and the monster now has 35.6% CC resistance (which we could
                        round off as necessary). 
                    </li>
                </ol>
                <p>
                    <strong>Example 2:</strong>
                </p>
                <ol>
                    <li>A monk with the Pandemonium rune is in Nightmare difficulty and casts Seven-Sided Strike on a
                        single enemy, resulting in a lot of possible 7-second stuns.
                    </li>
                    <li>The first hit stuns the monster and lasts for a full 7 seconds, but adds 70% CC resistance.</li>
                    <li>The second hit also successfully stuns the monster, and lands 0.4 seconds later after the first
                        hit. The 70% CC resistance is lowered to 50% because the game is currently on Nightmare
                        difficulty, and Nightmare difficulty has a CC resistance cap of 50% -- so the stun is 3.5
                        seconds long.  The 3.5-second stun gets applied, even though it is fully redundant with the
                        existing 7-second stun.  Since the new stun is shorter than the amount of time left on the
                        current stun, no additional CC resistance is added.  In effect, this second stun has no effect
                        at all..&lt;</li>
                </ol>
                <p>
                    <strong>Example 3:</strong>
                </p>
                <ol>
                    <li>A party of four monks attempts to stun-lock an Elite monster in Inferno difficulty. They are all
                        using Blinding Flash with the Self-Reflection rune, which blinds an enemy for 4 seconds.
                    </li>
                    <li>The first monk casts Blinding Flash and the monster is blinded for 4 seconds. It also now has
                        40% CC resistance.
                    </li>
                    <li>The second monk also casts Blinding Flash, but times it to land the instant the first one
                        ends. It lasts 2.4 seconds and increases the CC resistance to 64%.
                    </li>
                    <li>Both blinds wear off 6.4 seconds later. The third monk lands his Blinding Flash immediately
                        afterwards, which lasts 1.44 seconds. This increases the monster’s CC resistance to 78.4%.
                    </li>
                    <li>It's now been 7.84 seconds, and the fourth monk wants in on the action. She uses her Blinding
                        Flash. Even though the monster’s CC resistance is technically at 78.4% by now, it's capped at
                        65% because of the CC resistance caps in Inferno. So, the 4 second blind actually lasts for 1.4
                        seconds. This adds another 14% CC resistance, bringing the final to 92.4%. (The effective
                        resistance is still at the 65% cap, but the 92.4% is tracked under the hood for the stun
                        resistance to wear off.)
                    </li>
                    <li>The poor monster has now been blinded for a total of 9.24 seconds, and the monks are out of
                        Blinding Flashes. :(
                    </li>
                    <li>The next blind will occur when the first monk’s Blinding Flash comes off cooldown. Since
                        Blinding Flash has a 15 second cooldown, and only 9.24 seconds have passed, the party has to
                        wait for another 5.76 seconds. During this time, the monster loses 57.6% CC resistance, leaving
                        it at 34.8%. 
                    </li>
                    <li>The first monk uses his Blinding Flash as soon as it comes off cooldown. The 4 second blind is
                        reduced to 2.61 seconds thanks to 34.8% CC resistance, and the monster’s CC resistance goes up
                        another 26.1% to 60.9%.
                    </li>
                </ol>
                <p>
                    <strong>Example 4:</strong>
                </p>
                <p>Scenario 1</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Player 1 applies a 1 second stun, it lasts 1 second.  Monster has 10% CC resistance.</li>
                    <li>Player 2 applies a 6 second stun, it lasts 5.4 seconds.  Monster now has 64% CC resistance.</li>
                </ul>
                <p>Scenario 2</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Player 1 applies a 6 second stun, it lasts 6 seconds.  Monster now has 60% CC resistance.</li>
                    <li>Player 2 applies a 1 second stun, it lasts 0.4 seconds.  Monster now has 64% CC resistance.</li>
                </ul>
                <p>(Scenario 1 &amp; 2 demonstrate that this system allows consecutively chained CC effects to be
                    applied in any order.  In other words, the math is commutative.)
                </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p>We feel these changes should make CC abilities much more appealing (especially in those later
                    difficulty levels), and are currently targeting them to go out with patch 1.0.5. While that patch is
                    still a ways away, we encourage you to experiment with the math in the meantime, ask us any
                    questions you may have about how the new diminishing returns system will work, and share your
                    feedback!
                </p>
                <p> </p>
                <p>
                    <em>Wyatt Cheng is a Senior Technical Game Designer for Diablo III. His favorite Iron Chef is
                        Hiroyuki Sakai. A la cuisine!<span style="font-size: 12px; "> </span> 
                    </em>
                    <br/>
                    <style type="text/css">
                        #blog .detail #center {
                            width: 590px;
                            margin: 0px auto;
                        }

                        #blog .divider-down {
                            width: 100%;
                            height: 18px;
                            background: url('http://us.media3.battle.net/cms/gallery/KKZW0YDVPDT91334191716743.png?v=2') center center no-repeat;
                        }

                        #blog .divider-up {
                            width: 100%;
                            height: 18px;
                            background: url('http://us.media1.battle.net/cms/gallery/MO010OF9ESV11334191716770.png?v=2') center center no-repeat;
                        }

                        #blog .detail div.ctextheadline {
                            position: relative;
                            display: block;
                            text-decoration: none;
                            line-height: 1 !important;
                            font-family: Georgia !important;
                            margin-left: 3px;
                        }

                        #blog .detail div.ctextheadline h1 {
                            position: absolute;
                            top: 17px;
                            left: 30px;
                            color: #FFBF55 !important;
                            font-size: 23px !important;
                        }

                        #blog .detail div.cteaser, #blog .detail img, #blog .detail div.cteaserg {
                            -moz-border-radius: 4px;
                            -webkit-border-radius: 4px;
                            border-radius: 4px;
                            -moz-box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                            -webkit-box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                            box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                            border: 1px solid #372511;
                            padding: 1px;
                        }

                        #blog .detail div.cteaser, #blog .detail div.cteaserg {
                            width: 285px;
                            height: 144px;
                            margin: 8px 3px 0px 3px;
                            padding-top: 5px;
                            background-color: #1D100A;
                            float: left;
                        }

                        #blog .detail div.cteaser:hover {
                            border: 1px solid #CD9000;
                            background-color: #40200d;
                        }

                        #blog .detail .cteaser a.cteaserimg, #blog .detail .cteaserg div.cteaserimg {
                            display: block;
                            width: 125px;
                            height: 140px;
                            text-align: center;
                            float: left;
                        }

                        #blog .detail .cteaser a.cteaserimg img, #blog .detail .cteaserg div.cteaserimg img {
                            -moz-border-radius: 10px;
                            -webkit-border-radius: 10px;
                            border-radius: 10px;
                            -moz-box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                            -webkit-box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                            box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                            border: 1px solid #1D100A;
                            vertical-align: middle;
                            width: 109px;
                            height: 109px;
                            margin-top: 10px;
                            padding: 1px;
                        }

                        #blog .detail .cteaser a.cteasersummary, #blog .detail .cteaserg div.cteasersummary {
                            display: block;
                            padding-right: 3px;
                            line-height: 1.4 !important;
                            width: 157px;
                            height: 140px;
                            float: left;
                        }

                        #blog .detail .cteaser a.cteasersummary span.headline, #blog .detail .cteaserg div.cteasersummary span.headline {
                            color: #d19205 !important;
                            font-size: 17px !important;
                            text-weight: bold !important;
                        }

                        #blog .detail .cteaser a.cteasersummary span.summarytext, #blog .detail .cteaserg div.cteasersummary span.summarytext {
                            color: #ad8460 !important;
                            font-size: 12px !important;
                        }

                        .top-list tr:nth-child(2) td {
                            color: #F0E29A;
                            background-color: transparent;
                        }

                        .top-list-interior table tbody tr td {
                            background-color: none !important;
                            color: #EFC9A0 !important;
                            font-weight: normal !important;
                            vertical-align: top;
                        }

                        .top-list-interior table tbody tr:hover td {
                            color: #fff !important;
                        }

                        #blog .detail a img:hover {
                            border: 1px solid #CD9000;
                        }</style>
                    <style type="text/css">
                        .pullquote:before {
                            content: "\201C" attr(title) "\201D";
                            font-size: 1.2em;
                            display: block;
                            float: right;
                            width: 8em;
                            margin: 0.25em 1em 0.5em 0;
                            padding: 1em;
                        }</style>
                </p>
            </div>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="text">Diablo III Web APIs</title>
        <published>2012-08-31T18:39:22.942Z</published>
        <updated>2012-09-05T17:18:47.688Z</updated>
        <id>7118938</id>
        <link href="http://us.battle.net//d3/en/blog/7118938"/>
        <summary type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>With the recent release of character profiles on the Diablo III community website, we’ve also
                    introduced new Diablo III Community Platform APIs. These APIs allow fansite creators and other
                    community developers to access the same sort of game data available on our profile pages – along
                    with a little extra.
                </p>
            </div>
        </summary>
        <content type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>With the recent release of character profiles on the Diablo III community website, we’ve also
                    introduced new Diablo III Community Platform APIs. These APIs allow fansite creators and other
                    community developers to access the same sort of game data available on our profile pages – along
                    with a little extra.
                </p>
                <div class="divider-up">
                     
                </div>
                <h2>
                    What’s New?
                </h2>
                <p>The new APIs we've released fall into two categories: dynamic data and static game data.</p>
                <p>
                    <b style=" color:#F3E6D0;">Dynamic Data</b>
                    <br/>
                    The new dynamic data APIs include Career Profiles and Hero Profiles, which cover information that
                    changes regularly as people play the game.
                </p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Career Profiles are high-level summaries of a player’s accomplishments, and are associated with
                        a game account. Here, you’ll find a hero list, fallen hero list, details on the player’s
                        artisans, and information on game progress (such as overall quest completion).
                    </li>
                    <li>Hero Profiles contain hero-specific information, such as equipped items, skills, base
                        attributes, game progression information, and follower details.
                    </li>
                </ul>
                <p>
                    <b style=" color:#F3E6D0;">Static Game Data</b>
                    <br/>
                    The second category of APIs – static game data – includes Item, Follower, and Artisan APIs. Data
                    provided by these APIs doesn't generally change, and when it does, it’s generally accompanied with a
                    game patch.
                </p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Item information contains everything you need to know about an item. At this time, we are
                        providing information for generated items – items that are dropped or crafted in-game.
                    </li>
                    <li>Follower information allows you to get detailed skill information.</li>
                    <li>Artisan information allows you to get detailed information on what an Artisan has available at
                        each tier, including the recipes that can be learned and information about the recipes’
                        requirements.
                    </li>
                </ul>
                <div class="divider-down">
                     
                </div>
                <p>Check out the
                    <a href="http://us.battle.net/d3/en/forum/6916195/">DIII Community Platform API forum</a>
                    for more information, including API documentation and examples of how to reference them.
                </p>
                <script language="javascript">
                    document.getElementsByClassName("header-image")[0].title = "See? I TOLD you the servers needed better cooling!";
                </script>
                <style type="text/css">
                    #page-comments {
                        display: none;
                    }

                    #blog h2 {
                        font: normal 20px "Palatino Linotype", "Times", serif;
                        color: #F3E6D0;
                    }

                    #blog .divider-down {
                        width: 100%;
                        height: 72px;
                        background: url('http://us.media3.battle.net/cms/gallery/KKZW0YDVPDT91334191716743.png?v=2') center center no-repeat;
                    }

                    #blog .divider-up {
                        width: 100%;
                        height: 72px;
                        background: url('http://us.media1.battle.net/cms/gallery/MO010OF9ESV11334191716770.png?v=2') center center no-repeat;
                    }</style>
            </div>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="text">Meet Svetlana Quindt, the Female Barbarian</title>
        <published>2012-08-29T03:00:00.000Z</published>
        <updated>2012-09-05T17:18:58.971Z</updated>
        <id>7100053</id>
        <link href="http://us.battle.net//d3/en/blog/7100053"/>
        <summary type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>
                    <span style="font-size: 12px; ">At gamescom 2012 hosted earlier this month in Cologne, Germany, we
                        crowned Svetlana Quindt the winner of our Blizzard Costume Contest for her stunning cosplay of
                        the female barbarian from Diablo III. Check out a few snapshots of her costume 
                    </span>
                    <a href="http://eu.blizzard.com/en-gb/company/events/gamescom2012.html#gamescom:gallery"
                       target="_blank">at the event
                    </a>
                    <span style="font-size: 12px; "> and follow-up </span>
                    <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/kamuicosplay/sets/72157631190384414/" target="_blank">studio
                        session
                    </a>
                    <span style="font-size: 12px; "> below, and be sure to continue reading for a quick Q&amp;A!</span>
                </p>
            </div>
        </summary>
        <content type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>At gamescom 2012 hosted earlier this month in Cologne, Germany, we crowned Svetlana Quindt the winner
                    of our Blizzard Costume Contest for her stunning cosplay of the female barbarian from Diablo III.
                    Check out a few snapshots of her costume
                    <a href="http://eu.blizzard.com/en-gb/company/events/gamescom2012.html#gamescom:gallery"
                       target="_blank">at the event
                    </a>
                    and follow-up
                    <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/kamuicosplay/sets/72157631190384414/" target="_blank">studio
                        session
                    </a>
                    below, and be sure to continue reading for a quick Q&amp;A!
                </p>
                <p style="text-align: center; ">
                    <a class="lightbox"
                       href="http://us.media1.battle.net/cms/content_folder_media/DEGZK67L8F9K1346209588355.jpg?v=1"
                       style="width: 532px; height: 800px; ">
                        <img alt=""
                             src="http://media.wow-europe.com/events/gamescom-2012/gallery/gamescom-2012-photo0095.jpg"
                             style="width: 255px; height: 383px; "/>
                    </a>
                    <a class="lightbox"
                       href="http://us.media2.battle.net/cms/content_folder_media/3OLX38WEXRAZ1346209599137.jpg?v=1"
                       style="width: 532px; height: 800px; ">
                        <img alt=""
                             src="http://media.wow-europe.com/events/gamescom-2012/gallery/gamescom-2012-photo0114.jpg"
                             style="width: 255px; height: 383px; margin-left: 10px; margin-right: 10px; "/>
                    </a>
                </p>
                <p style="text-align: center; ">
                    <a class="lightbox" href="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7115/7837324742_12f5a1627c_c.jpg">
                        <img alt="" src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7115/7837324742_12f5a1627c_c.jpg"
                             style="width: 255px; height: 364px; "/>
                    </a>
                    <a class="lightbox" href="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8446/7837326108_0baa1131df_c.jpg">
                        <img alt="" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8446/7837326108_0baa1131df_c.jpg"
                             style="width: 255px; height: 364px; margin-left: 10px; margin-right: 10px; "/>
                    </a>
                </p>
                <div class="divider-up">
                     
                </div>
                <div>
                    <span style="font-family:georgia,serif;">
                        <strong>Q. How long did this particular piece take to create?</strong>
                    </span>
                </div>
                <div>
                    It took about a month of full-time work to create the costume. Some years ago it took months to
                    finish such a costume, but over the time I've learned a lot and knew this time just what to do and
                    how to avoid mistakes. So, it was a pretty fast project.
                </div>
                <div>
                     
                </div>
                <div>
                    <span style="font-family:georgia,serif;">
                        <strong>Q. What materials did you use for this costume?</strong>
                    </span>
                </div>
                <div>
                    The whole armor is made out of the thermoplastic materials Worbla and Wonderflex in a combination
                    with craft form. For the fabric parts, I used a lot of fake fur, furniture leather, or some orange
                    fabric. 
                </div>
                <div>
                     
                </div>
                <div>
                    <span style="font-family:georgia,serif;">
                        <strong>Q. Why the barbarian? What made you decide to cosplay this particular class from Diablo
                            III instead of one of the others?
                        </strong>
                    </span>
                </div>
                <div>
                    Well, I play a barbarian and a wizard. Last year, I made a
                    <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/kamuicosplay/sets/72157627318119863/" target="_blank">wizard
                        costume
                    </a>
                    based on the amazing artwork of Wei Wang. I'm a pretty big fan of his work and he made an awesome
                    painting of a kick-ass barbarian, too. I guess I have the right body shape for this class and just
                    love to build armored, bulky, and very detailed costumes. And I just love the wild, aggressive, and
                    very cool female barbarian in Diablo III. So, Wei Wang's barbarian artwork was just perfect for my
                    next project. 
                </div>
                <div>
                     
                </div>
                <div>
                    <span style="font-family:georgia,serif;">
                        <strong>Q. How long have you been an active cosplayer?</strong>
                    </span>
                </div>
                <div>
                    I started 2003 but only did it because everyone alse at the conventions in Germany did it. I really
                    fell in love with cosplaying in 2005 when World of Warcraft was released and I had this really crazy
                    idea of bringing my game character (the nightelf druid called Kamui) to "real" life. After five more
                    handmade druid tier sets, I can say that 2005 and World of Warcraft were the real start of my
                    cosplay carreer. 
                </div>
                <div>
                     
                </div>
                <div>
                    <span style="font-family:georgia,serif;">
                        <strong>Q. What advice would you give to people who are interested in getting into cosplay, or
                            are just starting out?
                        </strong>
                    </span>
                </div>
                <div>
                    Over the years the cosplay scene developed a lot. People share their own costume progress on
                    facebook or their blogs, make tutorials and are in many other ways very helpful. As a beginner it’s
                    pretty easy to learn a lot just by following the work of others and then make your very first own
                    steps in creating a costume. But besides doing your homework and research for some inspiration and
                    help, it’s also important to plan well. Start early enough and expect problems and mistakes. No
                    costume is done without some hard times full of frustration and desperation, but if you won’t give
                    up and keep on fighting, you’ll be successful. 
                </div>
                <div>
                     
                </div>
                <div>
                    <span style="font-family:georgia,serif;">
                        <strong>Q. What’s your favorite class in Diablo III, and why?</strong>
                    </span>
                </div>
                <div>
                    It's hard to decide between the wizard and the barbarian, but yeah, I guess it's the barbarian. I
                    just love to jump into a group of blood-thirsty demons and kick them back to hell with my Whirlwind.
                    I really like the wild and very aggressive style of the barbarian and the design of their huge and
                    bulky armor. 
                </div>
                <div class="divider-down">
                     
                </div>
                <p>Follow Svetlana's
                    <a href="https://www.facebook.com/KamuiCosplay" target="_blank">official cosplay page on Facebook
                    </a>
                    for additional photos and updates, or learn more about her work over at <a
                            href="http://www.kamuicosplay.com/" target="_blank">http://www.kamuicosplay.com/</a>.
                </p>
                <style type="text/css">
                    #blog .detail img {
                        -moz-border-radius: 4px;
                        -webkit-border-radius: 4px;
                        border-radius: 4px;
                        -moz-box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                        -webkit-box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                        box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                        border: 1px solid #372511;
                        max-width: 570px !important;
                        padding: 1px;
                    }

                    #blog .detail #center {
                        width: 590px;
                        margin: 0px auto;
                    }

                    #blog .divider-down {
                        width: 100%;
                        height: 18px;
                        background: url('http://us.media3.battle.net/cms/gallery/KKZW0YDVPDT91334191716743.png?v=2') center center no-repeat;
                    }

                    #blog .divider-up {
                        width: 100%;
                        height: 18px;
                        background: url('http://us.media1.battle.net/cms/gallery/MO010OF9ESV11334191716770.png?v=2') center center no-repeat;
                    }</style>
            </div>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="text">New Diablo Fan Art</title>
        <published>2012-08-24T17:00:00.000Z</published>
        <updated>2012-08-24T21:04:32.827Z</updated>
        <id>6986838</id>
        <link href="http://us.battle.net//d3/en/blog/6986838"/>
        <summary type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>The<a href="http://us.battle.net/d3/en/media/fanart/" target="_blank">Diablo Fan Art Section</a>has
                    been updated with two new pieces of fan artwork. Would you like to share your artistic talents with
                    the community?<a href="http://us.blizzard.com/en-us/community/fanart/rules.html" target="_blank">
                        Submit</a>your fan art today!
                </p>
            </div>
        </summary>
        <content type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>The<a href="http://us.battle.net/d3/en/media/fanart/" target="_blank">Diablo Fan Art Section</a>has
                    been updated with two new pieces of fan artwork.
                </p>
                <p> </p>
                <center>
                    <p>
                        <a href="http://us.battle.net/d3/en/media/fanart/?view#/fanart-0097" target="_blank">
                            <img alt=""
                                 src="http://us.media4.battle.net/cms/content_folder_media/X2UXD35UG4RD1345066403792.jpg?v=1"
                                 style="width: 188px; height: 118px;"/>
                        </a>
                        <a href="http://us.battle.net/d3/en/media/fanart/?view#/fanart-0096" target="_blank">
                            <img alt=""
                                 src="http://us.media4.battle.net/cms/content_folder_media/BG5I3PQW0PM71345066393260.jpg?v=1"
                                 style="margin-left: 5px; margin-right: 5px; width: 188px; height: 118px;"/>
                        </a>
                    </p>
                </center>
                <p>
                    <br/>
                    Would you like to share your artistic talents with the community?<a
                        href="http://us.blizzard.com/en-us/community/fanart/rules.html" target="_blank">Submit</a>your
                    fan art today!
                </p>
                <style type="text/css">
                    #blog .detail img {
                        -moz-border-radius: 4px;
                        -webkit-border-radius: 4px;
                        border-radius: 4px;
                        -moz-box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                        -webkit-box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                        box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                        border: 1px solid #300E0D;
                        padding: 1px;
                    }

                    #blog .detail td:hover > a img, #blog .detail a img:hover {
                        border: 1px solid #BA5E0B;
                    }</style>
            </div>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="text">Ahh, Fresh Meat!</title>
        <published>2012-08-24T02:30:00.000Z</published>
        <updated>2012-09-05T17:19:09.123Z</updated>
        <id>7054208</id>
        <link href="http://us.battle.net//d3/en/blog/7054208"/>
        <summary type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>
                    <span style="font-size: 12px; ">Feast your eyes on the "Diablo Butcher", a visceral rendition of
                        everyone's favorite cleaver-wielding brute 
                    </span>
                    <span style="font-size: 12px; ">by fan artist SeungHwan Jang</span>
                    <span style="font-size: 12px; ">. It's gruesome, a little terrifying, and (most importantly) </span>
                    <em style="font-size: 12px; ">bloody brilliant</em>
                    <span style="font-size: 12px; ">.</span>
                </p>
                <p>Take a look!</p>
            </div>
        </summary>
        <content type="xhtml">
            <div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
                <p>Feast your eyes on the "Diablo Butcher", a visceral rendition of everyone's favorite cleaver-wielding
                    brute <span style="font-size: 12px; ">by fan artist SeungHwan Jang</span>. It's gruesome, a little
                    terrifying, and (most importantly) <em>bloody brilliant</em>.
                </p>
                <p style="text-align: center; ">
                    <a class="lightbox"
                       href="http://us.media1.battle.net/cms/content_entry_media/QYRZDVRR8LAQ1345774709180.jpg?v=1">
                        <img alt="" src="http://cghub.com/files/Image/277001-278000/277438/122_max.jpg"
                             style="width: 550px; height: 342px; "/>
                    </a>
                </p>
                <p>To see more of SeungHwan's work, be sure to check out his page on
                    <a href="http://flcl38.cghub.com/" target="_blank">CGHUB.com</a>
                    or visit his personal website at<a href="http://www.sabzil.net/" target="_blank">
                        http://sabzil.net</a>.You can also find out more about how this piece was made <a
                            href="http://blog.naver.com/flcl38/20164393483" target="_blank">here</a>, on the artist's
                    personal blog. 
                </p>
                <style type="text/css">
                    #blog .detail img {
                        -moz-border-radius: 4px;
                        -webkit-border-radius: 4px;
                        border-radius: 4px;
                        -moz-box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                        -webkit-box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                        box-shadow: 0 0 20px #000000;
                        border: 1px solid #372511;
                        max-width: 570px !important;
                        padding: 1px;
                    }

                    #blog .detail td:hover > a img, #blog .detail a img:hover {
                        border: 1px solid #CD9000;
                    }</style>
            </div>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>